***MinJun (ybmj@vip.163.com) 精心製作 Patton中英雙語字幕***
製作&校對: MinJun (ybmj@vip.163.com)
(CHATTERING)
Ten ... hut!
立 ... 正！
(SILENCE)
(BUGLE PLAYS)
Be seated.
坐下。
(SHUFFLING)
Now, I want you to remember. . .
我要你們記住，. . .
. . .that no bastard ever won a war. . .
. . .當兵的打勝仗. . .
. . .by dying for his country.
. . .絕不是靠他去為國犧牲。
He won it. . .
而是要他讓. . .
. . .by making the other poor dumb bastard die for his country.
. . .對方當兵的個個都去送命。
Men. . .
各位都. . .
. . .all this stuff you've heard about America not wanting to fight. . .
. . .聽說了一大堆什麼美國人不想打仗. . .
. . .wanting to stay out of the war. . .
. . .想置身於戰爭之外的說法，. . .
. . .is a lot of horse dung.
. . .那全都是一些胡扯。
Americans. . .
美國人. . .
. . .traditionally love to fight.
. . .天生就是好鬥的，
All real Americans love the sting of battle.
真正美國人都愛自己的競賽。
When you were kids, . . .
當你們小時候，. . .
. . .you all admired the champion marble shooter, . . .
. . .都很欽佩彈珠高手、. . .
. . .the fastest runner, big-league ball players, the toughest boxers.
. . .都很崇拜賽跑冠軍、甲級棒球隊員、最棒的拳擊手。
Americans love a winner, . . .
美國人喜歡勝利者，. . .
. . .and will not tolerate a loser.
. . .不能容忍失敗者。
Americans play to win all the time.
美國人就是一心想贏。
I wouldn't give a hoot in hell for a man who lost and laughed.
我最看不起那些輸了還會滿臉歡笑的失敗者。
That's why Americans have never lost and will never lose a war, . . .
那也正是美國人絕不會輸、也絕不會打敗仗的原因，. . .
. . .because the very thought of losing. . .
. . .因為美國人一想到輸，. . .
. . .is hateful to Americans.
. . .就會覺得太可恥了。
Now, . . .
在這裡，. . .
. . .an army is a team.
. . .軍隊就是一個團隊。
It lives, eats, sleeps, fights as a team.
他們一起生活，一起吃飯、睡眠和戰鬥。
This individuality stuff is a bunch of crap.
那些講個性的文章，全都是一些胡扯。
The bilious bastards who wrote that stuff about individuality. . .
那些寫文章談論個人主義的混蛋，. . .
. . .for the Saturday Evening Post. . .
. . .在華盛頓郵報上發表，. . .
. . .don't know anything more about real battle than they do about fornicating.
. . .對什麼是戰爭和通姦，同樣是一無所知的。
Now we have the finest food and equipment, . . .
我們有世上最好的伙食和裝備，. . .
. . .the best spirit, . . .
. . .最好的士氣，. . .
. . .and the best men in the world.
. . .最優秀的戰士。
You know, . . .
說真的，. . .
. . .by God, I. . .
. . .老天，我. . .
...actually pity those poor bastards we're going up against. By God, I do.
...真的很可憐那些被我們打擊的狗雜種們。老天，真的。
We're not just going to shoot the bastards, . . .
我們不僅要殺死那些狗雜種，. . .
. . .we're going to cut out their living guts, . . .
. . .我們還要割開他們的肚皮，. . .
. . .and use them to grease the treads of our tanks.
. . .挖出他們的內臟為我們坦克的履帶加油。
We're going to murder those lousy Hun bastards by the bushel.
我們要大量殲滅那些德國鬼子。
Now, . . .
我知道，. . .
. . .some of you boys, . . .
. . .你們中有些人. . .
. . .I know, are wondering. . .
. . .我清楚，會擔心，. . .
. . .whether or not you'll chicken out under fire. Don't worry about it.
. . .自己上了火線會不會膽怯。你們用不著擔心。
I can assure you. . .
我敢保證各位. . .
. . .that you will all do your duty.
. . .都會忠於職守的。
The Nazis. . .
納粹. . .
. . .are the enemy.
. . .是我們的敵人。
Wade into them!
我們要狠狠地打擊他們！
Spill their blood! Shoot them in the belly!
讓他們血流成河！肝腦塗地！
When you put your hand. . .
當你們摸到. . .
. . .into a bunch of goo. . .
. . .你們的好朋友. . .
. . .that a moment before was your best friend's face, . . .
. . .那張血肉模糊的臉的時候，. . .
. . .you'll know what to do.
. . .你就會下決心了。
Now, there's another thing I want you to remember.
另外，我還要你們記住，
I don't want to get any messages saying we are "holding our position. "
我不想收到這樣的消息，說什麼我們在堅守陣地。
We're not "holding" anything. Let the Hun do that.
我們用不著去守，讓德國人去守吧。
We're advancing constantly, and we're not interested in holding on to anything. . .
我們要經常勇往直前，我們不用去堅守什麼陣地，. . .
. . .except the enemy.
. . .讓敵人去守吧。
We're going to hold onto him by the nose, and we're going to kick him in the ass.
我們要牽住敵人的鼻子，對準他們的屁股，
We're going to kick the hell out of him all the time...
把他們踢得靈魂出竅，
. . .and we're going to go through him like crap through a goose!
. . .把他們殺得望風而逃！
Now, . . .
這樣，. . .
. . .there's one thing. . .
. . .當你們回國後，. . .
. . .that you men will be able to say when you get back home.
. . .你們就可以說：你們沒白來！
And you may thank God for it.
這得感謝上帝！
Thirty years from now, when you're sitting around your fireside. . .
三十年以後，當你坐在火爐旁邊，. . .
. . .with your grandson on your knee, . . .
. . .你的腿上坐著孫子，. . .
. . .and he asks you, . . .
. . .他問你：. . .
. . ."What did you do in the great World War II?"
. . .二次大戰你都做了些什麼？
You won't have to say:
你用不著說：
"Well, . . .
唉，. . .
. . .I shoveled shit in Louisiana. "
. . .我在路易斯安那州鏟糞。
All right, now, you sons of bitches. . .
好了，現在你們都知道. . .
. . .you know how I feel.
. . .我是怎麼想的了。
Go on now, . . .
到現在，. . .
I will be proud. . .
我非常樂意. . .
...to lead you wonderful guys into battle anytime...
...率領你們這些出色的戰士去衝鋒...
. . .anywhere.
. . .陷陣。
That's all.
完了。
【 巴 頓 將 軍 】
1943年 突尼斯卡塞林隘路
(JEEPS RUMBLING)
(DOG BARKS)
The Arabs need food and clothing.
阿拉伯人需要食物與衣服。
They strip our dead before we can even bury them.
我們來不及埋葬死者就被他們剝光了。
Looks like the reports were pretty accurate.
看來那些報告相當精確。
Sixty-one armored vehicles, 45 tons of ammunition, ...
61輛裝甲車輛，45噸彈藥，...
. . .twenty-five 40mm guns, three self-propelled 105s.
. . .25門40mm炮，3輛自走式105榴炮。
Not counting mortars, machine guns, rifles, . . .
還有不計其數的迫擊炮、機槍、步槍、. . .
. . .pistols, telescopes, belt buckles, Gl socks.
. . .手槍、望遠鏡、腰帶扣、襪子。
One thousand, eight hundred men.
還有1800個死者。
(CHEERING)
摩洛哥拉巴特
立正。
(SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Our people salute you, general, . . .
我國人民向您致敬，將軍，. . .
. . .for your brilliant amphibious landing on the continent of Africa, . . .
. . .為您在非洲高明的兩棲登陸，. . .
. . .and for your enlightened administration of our country.
. . .以及明智的管理致敬。
I've enjoyed being here, Excellency.
我很高興來到這裡，閣下。
Naturally, I'd prefer to be in Tunisia fighting the Germans.
但我當然更想去突尼斯打德國人。
(BAND PLAYS)
"The lions in their dens tremble at his approach. "
當他走近之時，洞窟裡的獅子也會發抖。
I appreciate that, Excellency.
謝謝，閣下！
(BAND PLAYS)
Magnificent!
軍容盛壯！
I wish our troops looked that good.
但願我們的部隊也能像那樣。
Tell me, general, what do you think of Morocco?
將軍，請問您對摩洛哥的觀感？
I love it, Excellency.
閣下，我喜愛此地。
It's a combination of the Bible and Hollywood.
它綜合了聖經與好萊塢的特點。
第2軍軍部
-These men fight at Kasserine?
-Yes, sir.
卡塞林戰役是這些人打的？
是的，長官。
For the American Army to take a licking like that. . .
難怪美軍對德軍第一戰就被. . .
. . .the first time at bat against the Germans.
. . .打得這麼慘。
Up against Rommel, what we need is the best tank man we've got.
面對隆美爾，我們需要最優秀的坦克將領。
Somebody tough enough to pull this outfit together.
而且管理嚴厲，讓部隊紀律嚴明。
-Patton?
-Possibly.
巴頓？ 也許吧。
God help us.
上帝保佑我們！
(SIREN WAILS)
(SPEAKING IN ARABIC)
-Lieutenant!
-Sheesh.
中尉！ 噓。
. . .where is the duty officer?
. . .值勤官在哪裡？
Billy. . . .
畢理。 . . .
-I think he's in his quarters, shaving.
-Why isn't he here on duty?
想必他是在宿舍刮臉。  他為什麼不在這裡值班？
Guess he needed a shave.
我猜他需要刮刮臉。
We got a new commanding general due today.
新任的指揮官今天會到。
(CRASHING)
Who the hell's kicking me in the butt?
是哪個混蛋踢我屁股？
Oh, sorry, uh, sir!
啊，對不起。喔，長官！
-What were you doing down there, soldier?
-Trying to get some sleep, sir.
你躺地板上做什麼，當兵的？想要睡一會兒，長官。
Well, Get back down there, son.
啊，躺著吧，孩子。
You're the only son of a bitch in this headquarters that knows what he's trying to do.
整個司令部裡，就你一個人知道要幹什麼。
Yes, sir.
是，長官。
-Brad, how the hell are you?
-Fine, George. Good to see you.
布拉德！你好嗎？不錯，喬治，很高興見到你
Ah, We were all under the impression you wouldn't be here until 0900.
啊，我們都以為你9點鐘才能到達。
Yes, I gathered that.
是，我看得出來。
-Ah, you know my boy, Dick Jenson, Al Stiller.
-Yes.
-啊，你認識我的副官迪克·簡森、與艾爾·斯蒂爾。
-是的。
Brad, tell me, uh, . . .
布拉德，告訴我，啊，. . .
-What are you doing here?
-Ike wanted a report on Kasserine business.
你在這裡做什麼？
艾森豪威爾將軍要一份卡塞林戰役的報告。
Meanwhile, I'm staying here chair-headquarters of as an observer, . . .
同時，我留在你的司令部裡做觀察員，. . .
. . .but I report directly to Ike.
. . .但我直接向艾克報告。
A spying.
是個坐探！
Get me General Eisenhower's headquarters.
給我接通艾森豪威爾將軍司令部。
Tell me, Brad, . . .
告訴我，布拉德，. . .
. . .what happened at Kasserine? I heard it was a shambles.
. . .卡塞林戰役出了什麼事？我聽說一塌糊塗。
Apparently, everything went wrong.
顯然，似乎每件事都出了差錯。
We'd send over a 75-millimeter shell, the krauts would return an 88.
我們打出75毫米的炮彈，德軍就回敬88毫米的。
Their tanks are diesels.
他們用的是柴油機坦克。
And even when we managed to hit them, they kept on running. Our tanks, . . .
即使打中它們，它們也能照樣開。而我們的坦克，. . .
the men call them "Purple Heart boxes. "
士兵們稱呼它們「勳章棺材」。
One hot piece of shrapnel and the gasoline explodes.
只要一塊高溫彈片就能引起汽油爆炸。
Hmm, I warned them about the tank.
嗯，我警告過他們坦克的事。
You know, I talked to one of the soldiers about the half-tracks.
你知道嗎，我和一位士兵談過半履帶車。
I asked if the, ah, machine-gun bullets pierced the armor.
我問機槍子彈，啊，是否能夠打穿裝甲。
And he said, "No, sir.
他說，不，長官。
They bullets just come through one side and rattle around a bit. "
子彈打進去後，只是在車裡撞來撞去。
I understand we had a little trouble coordinating the air cover.
我聽說空中掩護也有問題。
The trouble was no air cover.
問題的是根本就沒有空中掩護。
-General Smith on the line, sir.
-Excuse me, Brad.
史密斯將軍接通了，長官。
請原諒，布拉德。
Bedell?
比爾？
Listen, I'm calling about, uh, Bradley and his job here.
喔，我打電話是想談談，啊，布拉德利和他在這裡的工作問題。
Look, I need a good number-two man, I want to make Brad my deputy commander, OK？
啊，我需要一位副手，我想要布拉德利當我的副官，行嗎？
You clear it with Ike?
你能請示艾克批准嗎？
All right, thanks, Bedell.
好的，謝謝你，比爾！
Now you're not spying for Eisenhower anymore, you're working for me.
現在你不用再為艾森豪威爾當坐探了，你為我幹活吧。
-Okay?
-Fine, okay.
好嗎？  好的。
Dick, you've got those stars?
迪克，你帶那些星星了嗎？
-Yes, sir.
-Let's get them on.
長官，帶了。
讓我們把它們戴上。
What's the matter, Brad? I've been nominated by the president.
布拉德，怎麼了？是總統親自提名的。
I know, but, uh, it doesn't become official until it's approved by the Senate.
我知道，但是，啊，要參議院通過才算正式。
Well, . . .
喔，. . .
. . .they have their schedule, and I have mine.
. . .他們有他們的時間表，我有我的。
George, . . .
喬治，. . .
. . .if you were named admiral of the Turkish Navy. . .
. . .如果你被提名做土耳其海軍上將，. . .
. . .I believe your aides could dip into their haversacks. . .
. . .我相信你的副官也能在他的背包中. . .
. . .and come up with the appropriate badge of rank.
. . .找出合用的軍階徽章來。
Anyway, congratulations. Premature congratulations.
總之，恭喜你。提前恭喜你！
You know, . . .
你知道，. . .
I think those stars look better on a green shirt.
我認為那些星星配上綠襯衫上更好看。
Did I ever tell you about the time I designed a uniform for tank crewmen?
我有沒有告訴你，那回我設計了坦克兵的制服？
It was, uh, green leather, had red stripes, . . .
它是，啊，綠色皮衣配上紅條紋，. . .
. . .and had sort of a row of brass buttons down across here.
. . .前面從上到下有一排銅扣子。
And topped off by a gold football helmet.
頭上是金色的橄欖球頭盔。
The Army rejected it, of course.
當然，被陸軍駁回了。
Goddamn, it was beautiful.
媽的，它真的非常漂亮
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Lloyd Fredendall is just leaving.
勞易德·弗雷德裡克要走了。
George, there's one other thing I put in my Kasserine report.
喬治，我在卡塞林戰報裡還提到一件事。
Some of our boys were just plain scared.
我們有些士兵被嚇壞了。
Well, that's understandable.
嗯，那是可以理解的。
Even the best foxhound is gun-shy the first time out.
即使是最好的獵狗，第一次聽到槍聲也會害怕。
I can remember, . . .
我還記得，
. . .any nothing frightened me as much as the idea of. . .
. . .讓我感到最害怕的是一想到. . .
. . .a bullet coming straight for my nose. I don't know why, but the. . .
. . .有一顆子彈直接射向我的鼻子。我不知道為什麼，但是，. . .
. . .image of a bullet coming right for my nose. . .
. . .一想到有顆子彈向我的鼻子打來，. . .
. . .was more horrible than any other possibility.
. . .就比什麼都可怕。
But like, I can understand that, George, with such a handsome nose.
這也難怪，喬治，因為你的鼻子長得非常漂亮。
You want to know why this outfit got the hell kicked out of it?
你知道這支部隊為何慘敗嗎？
A blind man could see it in a minute.
就連瞎子也能很快看出。
They don't look like soldiers, they don't act like soldiers.
他們不像當兵的，也不是當兵的料。
Why should they be expected to fight like soldiers?
又怎麼能指望他們去打勝仗呢？
You're absolutely right. The discipline's pretty poor.
你說的對，他們紀律非常渙散。
In about 15 minutes, we're going to start turning these boys. . .
15分鐘後，我們要讓他們開始變得. . .
. . .into fanatics, razors.
. . .像當兵的，紀律嚴明。
They'll lose their fear of the Germans.
讓他們見了德兵不再害怕，
I only hope to God they never lose their fear of me.
我只希望他們怕我。
Up bright and early, general? Uh, Breakfast?
您起得真早，將軍？ 啊，要用早餐嗎？
Am I to understand that all my officers have finished breakfast?
是不是所有的軍官都用過早餐了？
Uh, We're open from 6 till 8.
喔，我們從6點到8點供應早餐。
Most of the officers are just coming in, sir.
大部分軍官才剛來用早餐，長官。
Please inform these officers the mess hall is closed.
請通知這些軍官，現在已經停止供應早餐了。
But, sir, it's only a quarter to 8.
但是，長官，現在離8點還差一刻。
From now on, you will open at 6, and no one will be admitted after 6:15.
從此以後，你們6點開始供應早餐，6點15之後就不准進入餐廳。
Where are your leggings?
你的綁腿呢？
Leggings? Well, hell, general, sir, I'm a cook.
綁腿？喔，嗨，將軍，長官，我是伙夫。
You're a soldier！
你是軍人！
$20 fine.
罰款20美元。
Gentlemen, . . .
先生們，. . .
. . .from this moment any man. . .
. . .從此刻起，任何人. . .
. . .without leggings, without a helmet, without a tie, . . . .
. . .沒打綁腿，沒戴鋼盔或不系領帶，. . .
any man with unshined shoes or soiled uniform, . . .
穿著髒軍鞋或者髒軍服，. . .
. . .is going to be skinned.
. . .都會受到重罰。
This is a barracks. It's not a bordello.
這裡是軍營，不是妓院。
(CHATTERING)
-Morning, boy.
-Morning, sir.
早上好，孩子。 早上好，長官。
Ah, Doctor.
啊，醫官。
Morning, sir.
早晨好，將軍。
I understand you have two cases of, uh, self-inflicted wounds.
我聽說這裡有兩個，啊，自殘的病例。
Yes, sir, we do.
是的，將軍。
Uh, Get them out of here.
喔，把他們從這裡趕出去。
Sir, one has developed a very serious infection.
將軍，不過其中一個嚴重發炎。
I don't care if he dies, just get him someplace but out of here.
我不管他的死活，把他趕到別的地方。
He doesn't belong in the same room with men wounded in battle.
他不配與在戰鬥中負傷的人呆在一起。
-I'll see they'ld move, sir.
-One more thing, uh.
我會派人搬走他們，長官。
還有，啊。
There'll be no "battle fatigue" in my command. That's an order.
我的部隊今後不准有「戰鬥恐懼癥」，這是命令！
-Yes, sir.
-"Battle fatigue" is a free ride, a yellow-belly's sicket to the hospital.
好的，長官。
「戰鬥恐懼癥」是混蛋懦夫混進醫院的借口。
I'm not going to subsidize cowardice.
我不會放任這種懦夫行為。
Yes, sir.
是的，長官。
Uh, Doctor. . ., where's your helmet?
還有，醫官，你的鋼盔呢？
I don't wear a helmet when I'm in the hospital, general.
我在醫院裡不戴鋼盔，將軍。
Start.
開始戴上。
I can't use my stethoscope when I'm wearing my helmet.
我戴上鋼盔就不能戴聽診器了。
Well, . . .
那麼，
. . .then cut two holes in your helmet so that you can.
. . .那就在鋼盔打兩個洞，好讓你戴聽診器。
And get those yellow-bellies out of here, today.
把那些膽小鬼給趕出去，就在今天！
Hold it.
等等。
Turn right, here.
向右轉。
Sir, the battlefield is straight ahead.
長官，直走才是戰場。
Please don't argue with me. I can smell a battlefield.
別爭了，我已經聞到戰場的氣息了。
He was here just yesterday，George.
他昨天才去過，喬治。
It's over there. Turn right, damn it.
是那邊，向右轉，見鬼！
It was here.
就是這裡。
The battlefield was here.
過去的戰場就在這裡。
The Carthaginians defending the city, . . .
迦太基人守衛著他們的城市，. . .
. . .were attacked by three Roman legions.
. . .他們遭到三個羅馬軍團的進攻。
The Carthaginians were proud and brave, but they couldn't hold.
迦太基人英勇不屈，但堅守不住。
They were massacred.
他們慘遭屠殺。
Arab women. . .
阿拉伯婦女. . .
. . .stripped them of their tunics and their swords and lances.
. . .剝掉他們的軍服、刀劍和長矛。
The soldiers lay naked in the sun, . . .
死者暴曬在陽光下，. . .
. . .2000 years ago.
. . .二千年前。
I was here.
我也身在此地。
You don't believe me，do you, Brad？
你不相信我，是嗎，布拉德？
You know what the poet said.
正如詩人說的：
"Through the travail of ages. . .
「歷經世世代代. . .
amidst the pomp and toils of war, . . .
在戰爭的悲壯與羅網之中，. . .
have I fought and strove and perished, . . .
我戰鬥、奮爭與殞滅，. . .
countless times upon the star.
無數次在星空下。
As if through a glass and darkly, . . .
似乎像透過望遠鏡和黑暗，. . .
the age-old strife I see, . . .
我看見了古老的紛爭，. . .
where I fought in many guises Many names. . .
在那裡,我曾經以許多不同的身份與姓名戰鬥. . .
but always me. "
但我保持我的本色。」
You know who the poet was?
你知道那個詩人是誰嗎？
Me.
我。
德國非洲軍團指揮官
歐文·隆美爾元帥
Sir, the interrogation reports on the American prisoners. . .
將軍，在美軍戰俘的審訊報告中...
. . .captured in our victory at Kasserine.
. . .我軍在卡塞林戰勝俘獲的。
They are not very good soldiers, these Americans.
這些美軍不是合格的軍人。
I'm not so sure. . .
我不會這麼說. . .
. . .after only one battle.
. . .才交戰了一次。
Their tanks were no match for our guns.
是他們的坦克敵不過我們的大炮。
And neither was their leadership, sir.
他們的指揮也不行，將軍。
At Kasserine they were not under American command.
在卡塞林他們不是由美軍將領指揮的。
They were under the British General Anderson.
他們是有英國的安德森將軍指揮的。
British commanders and American troops, the worst of everything!
英國將領指揮美國部隊，這是最糟糕的組合！
I remind you that Montgomery is a British Commander.
我要提醒你，蒙哥馬利是英國將領。
And he has driven us half way across Africa.
而他吧我們趕出了半個非洲。
Anyway, we have met the Americans for the first time and defeated them.
不論如何，我們初次迎戰美軍而且擊敗他們。
I'm optimistic.
我感到樂觀。
You can afford to be an optimist, I can't.
你可以做樂觀者，可我不行。
There's an opportunity here now, for us to mount an offensive.
我們在這裡有機會發起攻勢。
We've concentrated on harassing the enemy's flank, draw strength away from the British.
我們專注於襲擾敵軍側面，吸引他的力量離開英軍。
However, It appears now, excuse me, . . .
不過，現在，借過，. . .
that we could split the African Corps, . . .
我們似乎可以分割非洲軍團，. . .
and drive through Rommel to the sea.
而且穿越隆美爾抵達海岸。
Sorry，Mel, but that territory has been reserved. . .
抱歉，麥爾，那個地區是保留給. . .
for General Sir Bernard Law Montgomery.
蒙哥馬利將軍的。
We're supposed to let him win this win no matter how long it takes him.
不論他要耗上多久，我們都應該讓他打贏這一仗。
They're entitled to have their hero. After all, . . .
他們應該有他們的英雄。畢竟，. . .
Montgomery did push Rommel clear across North Africa.
蒙哥馬利確實迫使隆美爾越過北非撤退。
What about the Americans? Don't they ... need a hero too?
那美國人呢？難道他們 ... 不需要他們的英雄嗎？
You have anybody in mind，George?
你心裡有人選嗎，喬治？
Excuse me, sir. Air Vice-Marshal Coningham is here with General Buford.
打擾了，長官。克寧漢姆空軍中將與布福德將軍來訪。
Uh, Excuse me, gentlemen, . . .
喔，抱歉，各位請迴避一下，. . .
while I ask our British friends what's happened to our air cover. Round one coming up.
讓我問問英國朋友我們的空中掩護是怎麼回事？第一回合要開始了。
Harry.  Buford.  How are you?
哈里。 布福德。 你好嗎？
-Here you are. -George, good to see you. -Good.
你們來了。  喬治，真高興見到你！  很好。
-Uh, George, You know Arthur Coningham.
-Sure.
啊，喬治，你認識亞瑟·克寧漢姆嗎？  當然認識。
Delighted to see you, general.
幸會，將軍。
I've heard so much about you.
久仰大名。
Uh, Gentlemen, uh, it appears there's been some slight misunderstanding here, . . .
喔，各位，啊，這裡似乎有一點誤會，. . .
. . .and Ike thought we ought to get it straightened it out.
. . .艾克認為我們現在應該進行溝通把事情弄清楚。
No, no. No misunderstanding.
不，不，不是誤會。
We're supposed to have Allied air cover, and we don't get it.
我們應該獲得盟軍的空中掩護，但我們沒有得到。
German planes are strafing my troops.
德軍飛機不斷掃射我軍。
If I may say so, general, I'm afraid your operation reports are inaccurate.
請容我說一句，將軍，你的作戰報告可能不準確。
Report? Three days ago, the Krauts took off after my command car ran my ass into a ditch.
報告？德軍三天前緊追我的指揮車把我趕進溝裡。
My staff has assured me we have complete air supremacy, . . .
我的參謀保證我們擁有完全的制空權，. . .
. . .everywhere in the Mediterranean.
. . .在地中海各處都有。
When I complained about lack of air cover, . . .
當我抱怨缺乏空中掩護時，. . .
. . .you said our troops were not battle-worthy.
. . .你說我軍缺乏戰鬥力。
You spoke of the, uh, discredited practice of using air force as. . .
你提到了，啊，「無公信力地利用空軍作為. . .
. . .an alibi for lack of success on the ground.
. . .地面戰鬥不成功的借口。」
It's bad enough I have to wet-nurse Montgomery, I don't have to stand for that.
我當蒙哥馬利的奶媽已經夠糟了，我可不想再吃這一套！
I sincerely apologize for that remark, whoever made it.
我為那種說法誠懇道歉，不論是誰說的。
And I promise you one thing, general.
並且我向你承諾一件事，將軍：
You will see no more German planes.
你不會再看到德軍飛機了。
(CHICKEN SQUAWKS)
You were discussing, uh, air supremacy, Sir Arthur.
你們剛才還在談論，什麼，制空權，亞瑟爵士。
(HORN HONKS)
(GUNFIRE)
Damn door won't open!
該死的門打不開！
By God, By God, that's enough!
老天，老天，我受夠了！
Get that thing out of here!
把那玩藝兒開走！
Come on, you bastards! Take a shot at me, right in the nose!
來啊，混蛋！對準我的鼻子打！
Get back in here, George! We need a corps commander, not a casualty.
回來，喬治！我們需要指揮官，不是傷員！
How the devil did you manage to stage that?
你怎麼會想到用手槍去打飛機？
I don't know, . . .
我不知道，. . .
. . .but if I could find the Nazis sons of bitches flying those things, . . .
. . .不過要是我見到這次空襲的納粹飛行員，. . .
. . .I'd give them each a medal.
. . .我會給他們每個人都頒發勳章的！
Can't get over how cold it gets in the desert.
我受不了沙漠這麼冷。
Awfully cold, sir.
冷得可怕，長官。
Rommel's out there somewhere waiting for me.
隆美爾在某個地方等著我呢。
Yes, sir.
是的，長官。
You know. . .
你知道. . .
. . .if I had my way, I'd send that genius son of a bitch. . .
. . .如果我能作主，我會送給那個混蛋天才. . .
. . .an engraved invitation in iambic pentameter.
. . .一首雕刻好的邀請詩。
A challenge in two stanzas to meet me alone in the desert.
用二組十四行詩，邀請他到沙漠來我決鬥！
I'll deliver it.
我願意去送戰書。
Rommel in his tank and me in mine.
隆美爾開他的坦克，我開我的。
We'd stop about 20 paces. We'd get out and shake hands.
我們大約在20步距離停車，出來握手。
Then we'd button up and do battle, just the two of us.
然後我們關起艙蓋作戰，就只有我們兩個。
That battle would decide the outcome of the war.
那場戰鬥將決定戰爭的勝負。
It's too bad jousting's gone out of style.
可惜，現在已經不流行決鬥了。
It's like your poetry, general.
就像你的詩，將軍。
It isn't part of the 20th century.
它不屬於20世紀
Maybe you're right, Dick.
你說的對，迪克。
The world grew up.
世界長大了。
Hell of a shame.
真可惜。
Dick, I want a 24-hour guard put around this area.
迪克，我要這裡設置24小時警衛
If we don't, the damn Arabs will dig them up just to get their clothes.
不然，可惡的阿拉伯人會挖出死人剝光衣服。
Yes, sir.
遵命，將軍。
Our graves aren't gonna disappear like everybody else's who fought here.
我們的墳墓不應像其他在這裡戰鬥過的人那樣消失。
The Greeks, the Romans, the Carthaginians.
希臘人、羅馬人、迦太基人。
God, how I hate the 20th century.
老天，我真恨20世紀！
柏林
希特勒的參謀長約德爾上將
Captain Steiger reporting, General.
史泰格上尉報到，將軍。
Come with me, Steiger.
跟我來，史泰格。
Field Marshal Rommel, I hope you are feeling better.
隆美爾元帥，希望你感覺好點了。
Captain Steiger has been assigned to research General Patton.
史泰格上尉奉命來研究巴頓。
Very well. What do you have for me?
很好，你有什麼要告訴我？
General Patton comes from a military family.
巴頓將軍出自軍人世家
His grandfather was a hero of the American Civil War.
他祖父是美國內戰的英雄。
He was educated at the Virginia Military Institute and West Point.
他曾在維吉尼亞軍校與西點軍校受訓。
You're not telling me anything about the man.
你沒告訴我，關於他個性方面的事。
He writes poetry and believes in reincarnation.
他喜歡寫詩，而且相信輪迴。
He's one of the richest officers in the American Army.
他是美國陸軍中最有錢的軍官之一。
He prays on his knees, but curses like a stable boy.
他虔誠祈禱，但滿嘴髒話。
He has one standing order. "Always take the offensive, never dig in."
他有一道常設命令：「永遠進攻，永不固守。」
In 15 minutes we meet with the Fuehrer.
15分鐘後我們將晉見元首。
He will want to know how you plan to deal with Patton's forces？
他想知道，你計劃怎麼來對付巴頓的軍隊？
I will attack and annihilate him!
我會進攻而且消滅他！
Before he does the same to me.
在他先下手之前。
《坦克攻擊》隆美爾著
General?
將軍？
What is it？
什麼事？
Sir, we intercepted a German radio message.
長官，我們截聽到德軍通信。
Rommel's 10th Panzer is going to hit us near El Guettar.
隆美爾的第十裝甲師將在艾古塔進攻我們。
Rommel, huh?
隆美爾，是嗎？
(Mule Brays)
(驢叫聲)
All my life. . .
我一生都. . .
. . .I've wanted to lead a lot of men in a desperate battle.
. . .都想要率領許多人決一死戰。
Now I'm going to do it.
現在我要這樣做了。
Look.
看。
Battalion strength at least.
至少是營級兵力。
They haven't spotted our positions yet, general.
他們還沒發現我們的陣地，將軍。
They'll get an education in about 10 seconds.
在10秒鐘後，他們就會上一課。
Wait till they get a dose of that artillery fire.
等待他們的是遭受炮火轟擊。
Commence firing. Fire at will.
開始射擊，自選目標。
Commence firing. Fire at will. Commence firing. Fire at will.
開始射擊，自選目標。開始射擊，自選目標。
What a hell of a waste of fine infantry.
真是浪費了優秀的步兵！
-Get General Bradley on the radio.
-Yes, sir.
用無線電聯絡布拉德利將軍。
是，長官。
Sir, I can't raise him.
長官，我聯絡不到他。
Get voer there，Dick. Tell them to hit them on their right flank. We'll hold them by the nose. . .
去他那邊，迪克。告訴他猛攻敵軍右側。我們在這裡牽制住敵人. . .
. . .and kick them in the ass. Go on!
. . .我們前後夾擊敵軍，快去！
Put him in my car.
把他放進我車子裡。
(PLANE WHINES)
Rommel. . .
隆美爾. . .
. . .you magnificent bastard. I read your book!
. . .你這個高貴的大混蛋，我讀過你的書！
Captain Richard N. Jenson was a fine boy, . . .
理查德·簡森上尉是名優秀青年，. . .
. . .loyal, unselfish and efficient.
. . .忠誠，無私而且有能力。
I am terribly sorry.
我極為哀傷。
There are no coffins here since there is no wood.
因為這裡沒有樹木所以沒有棺材。
We will have a trumpeter and an honor guard, . . .
我們有鼓手與儀仗隊，. . .
...but we will not fire the volleys, as it would make people think an air raid was on.
...但不鳴槍致敬，因為那會讓人們誤以為有空襲。
I enclosed a lock of Dick's hair in a letter to his mother.
我在給迪克母親的信裡裝了一束他的頭髮。
He was a fine man and a fine officer, . . .
他生前是個好小伙，也是名好軍官，. . .
. . .and he had no vices.
. . .而且他沒有劣跡。
I shall miss him a lot.
我會非常想念他。
I can't see the reason such fine young men get killed.
我不明白，這樣優秀的青年，為什麼會死。
There are so many battles yet to fight.
今後還有很多仗要打。
英軍與美軍在突尼斯會師
Battle-weary, but victorious, American Gls and. . .
疲憊但是獲得勝利的美國大兵與英國. . .
...Tommies of the British 8th Army meet in an Allied victory celebration...
...英軍第八軍團的士兵勝利會師，歡聚...
. . .at Wadi Akarit in North Africa.
. . .於北非瓦地阿拉利特。
For the first time in this war, Broadway and Piccadillyjoin hands！
這是戰爭中美軍與英軍的首次會師，
這是百老匯和皮卡迪利大街的會師！
蒙哥馬利繼續推進
Meanwhile, General Montgomery, hero of El-Alamein...
同時，艾爾·阿拉曼的英雄蒙哥馬利將軍...
...continues to lead his veteran and victorious British 8th Army...
...繼續率領他久經沙場的英國第八軍團勝利之師...
...in a relentless drive against Rommel's vaunted Africa corps.
...不斷追擊著名的隆美爾非洲軍團。
It is obvious that North Africa will soon be lost.
很明顯，北非很快就會丟失。
We must now anticipate the enemy's next move.
我們現在必須預測敵軍的下一步行動。
I shall expect a staff report within 24 hours.
That will be all.Thanks everybady!
我在24小時內要拿到報告。
這是當務之急。謝謝各位！
Steiger, you have said nothing.
史泰格，你什麼也沒說。
I wasn't asked anything.
沒有人問我。
I'm asking you now.
You think Patton will attack Sardinia?
我現在問你，你認為巴頓會進攻撒丁島嗎？
Don't，sir.(SPEAKS IN GERMAN)
將軍，他不會
And why not?
為什麼不會？
Patton, sir ... is a military historian.
長官，巴頓 ... 是軍事史家。
He knows that Sicily, not Sardinia, has always been the key to Italy.
他知道意大利之鑰，一向是西西里而非撒丁島。
If Patton has his way he will attack Sicily at Syracuse, as the Athenians did.
如果巴頓能作主，他會像雅典人一樣進攻西西里的錫拉庫扎
Steiger, this is the twentieth century!
史泰格，現在是20世紀！
But you must understand, sir, Patton is a sixteenth-century man.
但是長官，你必須瞭解，巴頓是一個16世紀的人。
May I read an example?
我可以念一個例子嗎？
Yes.
可以
"On a dark street in New York 1922, wearing white tie and tails. . .
「1922年在紐約的一條黑暗小巷，繫著白色領帶身穿燕尾服的
". . .Patton saw three men pushing a young girl into the back of a truck.
「巴頓看見三個男子推一位年輕女孩上卡車。
"He leaped out of his car, produced a revolver. . .
「他跳出他的車子，拔出左輪手槍. . .
". . .and forced the men at gunpoint to release the girl."
「. . .逼那些男子釋放那個女孩。」
It turned out that the girl was the fiancee of one of the men.
原來那個女孩是其中一位的未婚妻。
They were merely helping her into the truck.
他們只是幫助她上卡車。
What could be more revealing?
還有什麼比這更明顯的？
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不懂你在說什麼？
Don Quixote encounters six merchants of Toledo and saves Dulcinea's virtue!
唐吉訶德迎戰六個商人而拯救杜爾西內亞。
Who the devil is Dulcinea?
杜爾西內亞是誰？
Don't you see, sir?
你看不出來嗎，長官？
Patton is a romantic warrior lost in contemporary times.
巴頓是迷失在現代的浪漫戰士。
The secret of Patton is the past.
巴頓的秘密是生活在過去。
He'll urge an attack on Sicily because that's what the Athenians did!
他會力主進攻西西里的因為那是雅典人做過的事。
阿爾及利亞 莫斯塔加納姆
General Bradley's done a tremendous job with 2nd Corps.
布拉德利將軍率領第二軍團進展良好。
He's moved into Bizerte and taken over 41,000 prisoners.
他已進入比塞大，而且俘獲41,000人。
Good. Very good.
好，很好。
You're not surprised, are you, general? After all, you trained that outfit.
你不會感到意外，是嗎，將軍？畢竟那是你訓練出來的部隊。
-Uh, Excuse me, general.
-Hmm?
打擾了，將軍。  嗯 ？
Sir, this is interesting. We've discovered Rommel wasn't present at El Guettar.
將軍，這很有意思。我們發現隆美爾沒在艾古塔現身。
-Who says so?
-G2, sir.
誰說的？
長官，參謀部說的。
Are they telling me that when we took 10th Panzer, Rommel was in Berlin with an earache?
難道他們是想告訴我，
當我們與第十裝甲師交戰時隆美爾在柏林治療耳朵？
Severe nasal diphtheria, sir.
是嚴重的鼻炎，長官。
G2 Also reports that Hitler probably retained Rommel in Berlin. . .
還有，參謀部還報告說希特勒把隆美爾留在了柏林. . .
. . .because things were going badly for the Africa Corps.
. . .是因為非洲軍團戰況不利。
He didn't want his favorite general to lose face.
他不願意讓他的愛將丟臉。
Well, I'm my favorite general, and I don't like to be told. . .
啊，我是我自己的愛將，我可不喜歡有人告訴我. . .
. . .that some second-stringer is up against me. Then I lose face.
. . .與我對抗的是二流人物。那樣我會丟臉的！
Who the hell are you, anyway?
你又是什麼人，哪來的？
General, this is Lieutenant Colonel Codman. Your new aide.
將軍，這是考德曼中校，你的新副官。
Well, Codman. I pulled your name off the list because I know your family.
對了，考德曼。我選中你，是因為我認識你家人。
I'm glad you did, sir.
我很高興你選中我，長官。
Codman，Rommel is the best the krauts have, and I kicked the hell out of him.
考德曼，隆美爾是德軍最優秀的將領，而且我狠狠地修理了他。
Now my own G2 section is trying to tell me he wasn't even there.
我的參謀部卻告訴我，他根本不在場！
But, general, he undoubtedly planned the German battle.
但是將軍，他無疑策劃了德軍的作戰。
If you defeat Rommel's plan, you've defeated Rommel. Isn't that true, Sir?
如果你擊敗了隆美爾的計劃，也就是擊敗了隆美爾。不是那樣嗎，長官？
Codman, . . .
考德曼，. . .
-Want you have a drink with me this night.
-Yes, sir.
-我邀你今晚喝一杯。
-是，長官。
I have a plan for the invasion of Sicily.
我有一套進攻西西里的計劃
I want to make sure I get it approved. You can help me.
我想確保它獲得批准。你可以幫助我。
I want to give a dinner for General Alexander.
我想邀亞歷山大將軍共進晚宴。
Get to him before Montgomery does.
搶在蒙哥馬利前說服他。
This will be strictly a formal affair, Codman, but, uh, purely social.
考德曼，這可是完全正式的宴會，但，又是，純社交性的。
-By that I mean, um, purely political.
-Yes, sir.
我是說，啊，純政治性的
是的，長官。
I want the finest food, the best wine available.
Everything, comme il faut(FRENCH).
我要盡可能最好的食物和最好的酒。事事都要正確。
(SPEAKS lN FRENCH)
Entendu, mon General.
我瞭解，將軍。
Quelque chose de vraiment special.
要很特別的東西，你要吩咐下去。
iA va sans dire.
將軍想邀請誰？
Le Marechal Alexander et son Chef D'etat-major,
peut-etre Taylor.
亞歷山大元帥與他的參謀長，或許還有泰勒。
Pas trop de monde,plutot intime, d'accord?
不要太多，但當然要最親近的，行嗎？
D'accord, mon General.
行，將軍。
Oh, Thank you.
喔，謝謝你。
George, this is really splendid wine.
喬治，這真是佳釀好酒。
Thank you, Arthur.
謝謝你，亞瑟。
Thank you.
謝謝你！
Sir Harold, I think it was Alcibiades in the Peloponnesian War. . .
哈羅德爵士，我記得阿爾喀德斯在的伯羅奔尼撒戰爭中. . .
. . .415 B.C., . . .
. . .公元前415年，. . .
. . .he said, "If Syracuse falls, all Sicily falls, and then ltaly."
. . .他說:"若錫拉庫扎失陷,整個西西里就會失陷,然後是意大利。"
He knew, you see, that Syracuse was the jugular of the island.
他知道，大家清楚，錫拉庫扎是整個西西里的要害。
And old Alcibiades always went for the throat.
古老的阿爾喀德斯每次都攻其要害。
I propose to take Sicily in the same way.
我建議以同樣方式攻取西西里。
-How's it going?
-The old man has them in his pocket.
情況如何？
我認為老頭子已經得手了。
Now, according to my plan, . . .
依照我的計劃，. . .
. . .General Montgomery will land here.
. . .蒙哥馬利將軍在這裡登陸。
I'll hit the beaches here, take Palermo.
我在這裡登陸，攻下巴勒莫。
Monty will drive north along the coast road, I'll come due east, . . .
蒙蒂沿海岸道路北上，我向正東推進，. . .
. . .take Messina, and cut off the German escape route.
. . .攻下墨西拿，切斷德軍退路。
Yes. . . .
好。. . .
Well, it looks like an interesting plan，George.
好啊，那個計劃看來不錯，喬治。
Well, gentlemen, to the conquest of Sicily.
各位，祝征服西西里！
Well, to the conquest of Sicily.
好，祝征服西西里！
To Sicily!
祝征服西西里！
You know, George, you'd have made a great marshal for Napoleon. . .
我說，喬治，你可能會是拿破侖的優秀元帥. . .
. . .if you'd lived in the 18th century.
. . .如果你活在18世紀的話。
Oh, but I did, sir Harold. I did.
啊，我以前就是，哈羅德爵士！我以前就是。
阿爾及爾 盟軍總部
Morning. Is General Smith in?
早安，史密斯將軍在嗎？
-I believe he's in the lavatory, sir.
-Thank you.
他大概在洗手間，長官。  謝謝你！
-Ah, there you are, Bedell.
-Monty.
啊，原來你在這兒，畢托。  蒙蒂。
Bedell, I've been giving a good bit of thought to the Sicily operation.
畢托，我仔細考慮過西西里作戰計劃。
Yes?
怎麼樣？
I, uh, I assume we're alone.
我想這裡沒別人吧。
You know Georgie Patton's already discussed his plan with Alexander.
你聽說喬治·巴頓已經與亞歷山大討論過他的計劃了吧。
I realize that, . . .
我聽說了，. . .
. . .but I have an idea that his plan may lead to an absolute disaster.
. . .但是我覺得他的計劃會導致絕對的災難。
Oh?
喔？
Bedell, look.
畢托，你看。
This is Sicily.
這個是西西里。
Now then, according to Patton's plan, . . .
那麼，依照巴頓的計劃，. . .
. . .I would attack Syracuse here, . . .
. . .我進攻錫拉庫扎，這裡，. . .
. . .and he would attack Palermo up here.
. . .他進攻巴勒莫，到這裡。
Now, obviously our forces would be divided.
現在，我們的兵力明顯會被分散了。
And just obviously, they could be chopped up piecemeal.
同樣明顯的是，我們可能被各個擊破。
Now, then, what I propose, and what I shall insist on, by the way. . .
現在，我建議，而且我也堅持，我是說. . .
. . .is this.
. . .這裡。
(MONTGOMERY Blowing)
I will land at Syracuse as planned.
我依計劃在錫拉庫扎登陸。
But the Americans, the Americans will land here, at Gela.
但是美軍，美軍在這裡，在基拉登陸。
I will advance north to Messina, the Americans protecting my flank.
我向北推進前往墨西拿，美軍掩護我的左側。
After all, Messina is the key.
畢竟，墨西拿是關鍵。
It's the reason for invading Sicily.
它是進攻西西里的原因。
I'll discuss your plan with Ike.
我會與艾克討論你的計劃。
I'm sure he'll give it serious consideration.
我相信他一定會認真考慮的。
-Amusing, isn't it?
-What?
真有趣，不是嗎？  什麼？
That the final plans for the invasion of Sicily. . .
進攻西西里的最終計劃. . .
. . .should have been put forward in an Algerian lavatory.
. . .竟然是在阿爾及利亞的洗手間裡提出來的。
George, I've bad news for you about your Sicily plan of afraid.
喬治，恐怕我有關於你的西西里計劃的一個壞消息。
Ike has turned it down.
艾克否決了它。
He feels that since the Italians will be defending their native soil for the first time. . .
他認為，因為這是意大利人首次保衛自己國土. . .
. . .and since the German resistance is stiffening, our force shouldn't be divided.
. . .並且德軍抵抗正在增強，所以我們不應分散兵力。
-Well, ah, where do my people land, then?
-In the Gulf of Gela.
那麼，啊，我的部隊在哪裡登陸？  在基拉海灣。
What for? There's nothing there but a beach.
為什麼？那裡只有海灘
Yes, but ... it puts you in a good position to support Montgomery.
是的，但 ... 那能使你進入有利位置支援蒙哥馬利。
And, uh, where does Montgomery land?
那麼，蒙哥馬利在哪裡登陸？
Well, he'll land in Syracuse and drive north to Catania, possibly even Messina.
是的，他在錫拉庫扎登陸，並且向北進往卡塔尼亞，或許甚至到墨西拿。
And you'll be alongside, protecting his left.
你將在旁並進，保護他的左側。
I see.
我明白了。
In other words, we get the burden again while good old Monty gets the glory.
換句話說，我們再度挑起重擔，然而讓老蒙蒂唾手得到榮耀？
Ike had to consider all points of view.
艾克必須考慮各方面的意見。
He made his decision not as an American, but as an Ally.
他不是以美國人，而是以盟友的身份作出決定的。
Had it been the other way around, I assure you, Monty would protest.
如果是反過來，我確信蒙蒂一定會抗議。
You know, I, . . .
你知道，我，. . .
. . .I've ... been in the Army 30 years.
. . .我已 ... 從軍已經三十年了。
When I get an order, I say, "Yes, sir. " And I do my damnedest to carry it out.
當我接到命令時，我總是說：「遵命，長官。」 而且盡力執行它。
But, . . .
不過，. . .
this is what happens when your commander stops being an American and starts . . .
這種事情的發生，就是當你的指揮官不再是美國人而開始. . .
. . .being an Ally.
. . .是盟友時。
Here's the gangster Patton,
landing at Gela with his Seventh Army.
這就是悍匪巴頓，帶著他的第七軍團在基拉登陸。
This film was captured after the landing.
這部影片是登陸後繳獲的。
I didn't realize he was so tall.
我不知道他有這麼高。
Over six feet.
六英尺以上。
He's constantly giving personal commands.
他不斷地發號施令。
Obviously they now have two prima donnas in Sicily, Montgomery and Patton!
顯然，他們在西西里有兩個唱主角的，蒙哥馬利和巴頓。
There's another three-star general.
還有一個三星級將軍是誰？
General Bradley ... , commander of the American II Corps.
布拉德利將軍 ... ，美軍第二軍團的軍長
He looks like a common soldier.
他看起來像個普通士兵。
He is most capable, yet unpretentious.
他非常富有能力，但卻很低調。
Unusual for a general.
是一個不尋常的將軍。
Sorry！
對不起！
I don't think I've made myself clear, sir.
我想我是沒說清楚，長官。
It's true, Montgomery met the toughest resistance of this campaign there at Catania.
蒙哥馬利確實在卡塔尼亞那裡遇到本戰役最堅強的抵抗。
However, if we're. . .
但是，如果我們要求. . .
Perfectly clear.
十分明顯，
Old Monty is as stuck as a bug on flypaper.
老蒙蒂會像被粘住的蒼蠅。
Yes, sir. But this order from General Alexander. . .
是的，長官。但這是亞歷山大將軍的命令. . .
. . .directing you to give up the Vizzini-Caltagirone road to General Montgomery.
. . .命令你讓出博西斯道路交給蒙哥馬利。
[Mocking British Accent] Well, then, old Bradley will have to slug, slug, mind you, . . .
[嘲笑英國人的口吻] 那麼，老布拉德利就必須爬行，請你注意是爬行，. . .
. . .his way up center of the island over those tough mountain roads, won't he?
. . .穿過本島中部的困難山路，不是嗎？
Yes, sir.
是的，長官。
Messina, Bell.
墨西拿，比爾。
Messina! . . .
墨西拿！. . .
. . .That's the heart of it.
. . .它是這次作戰的核心。
If they'd followed my plan, I'd be there by now.
如果他們照我的計劃，我現在已經到那裡了。
I'd cut off the retreat of every goddamn German on this island!
我會切斷島上每一條德軍與意軍的退路！
Now, you know what I'm gonna do?
現在，你知道我要作什麼？
First, I'm go to Palermo.
首先，我要去巴勒莫。
Then, I'm still beat that limey son of a bitch at Messina if it's the last thing I ever do!
然後，我拼了命也要比英國佬先進入墨西拿！
Hey, what's all this talk about taking the Vizzini road away from 2nd Corps?
嗨，有人說要第二軍讓出博西斯道路是怎麼回事？
General Alexander's orders. The road goes to Montgomery.
亞歷山大將軍的命令把道路讓給蒙哥馬利。
No, that road was assigned to me.
不，那條路是指定給我用的。
Well, How can I get north without that? You know the terrain there.
嗯，我沒有它怎麼向北推進？你知道北面的地形。
Sorry, Brad. But Monty's run into tough opposition, very tough.
抱歉，布拉德。但是蒙蒂碰上頑強的抵抗，很頑強的抵抗。
Now, You wouldn't be taking advantage of this situation, would you, George?
現在，你不會利用這個形勢吧，你會嗎，喬治？
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不懂你在說什麼。
Now, without that road, your whole army, except for my 2nd Corps, would be out of a job.
現在沒那條路，你的整個軍團，除我的第二軍外，全都無事可做。
-Free for you to go into Palermo, if you thought that.
-Who said anything about Palermo?
如果你想的話，可以自行前往巴勒莫。
誰說過什麼巴勒莫？
I can read a map.
我看得懂地圖。
Does Alexander know you've pushed out this far?
亞歷山大知道你推進到這麼遠了嗎？
That's a reconnaissance in force.
那是軍力威懾偵察。
George, . . .
喬治，. . .
...are you tell me, I've got to slug it out over those mountains with heavy resistance, ...
...你是不是想說，我必須在山區冒著強烈抵抗緩緩前進，...
...just so you can make a bigger splash than Monty?
...僅僅是為了讓你比蒙蒂更出風頭？
General, . . .
將軍，. . .
. . .I just follow my orders, . . .
. . .我只是遵守命令，. . .
. . .like the simple old soldier I am.
. . .我只不過是一個單純的老兵。
General Bradley.
布拉德利將軍。
Sir, General Alexander has heard we're moving west.
長官，亞歷山大將軍聽說了我們向西推進。
He says here, "Stop immediately, go no farther than Agrigento.
他說，「立即停止，不得超越阿格利真托。
Repeat, stop immediately. "
複述，立即停止。」
That's what you think it says.
那只是你的理解。
I think it was garbled in transmission.
但我認為通信有干擾。
Ask them to re-transmit the message. It takes tiems off a lot of.
請他們再發一遍。但你別急著去辦。
That'll take half a day at least.
那至少要花半天時間。
Yes, sir.
是，長官。
Well, Brad, . . .
那麼，布拉德，. . .
. . .where were we?
. . .我們談到哪了？
We were talking about a simple. . .
我們談到一位單純的. . .
. . .old soldier.
. . .老兵。
Look at that, gentlemen.
看看那裡，各位。
Compared to war, . . .
與戰爭相比，. . .
. . .all other forms of human endeavor shrink to insignificance.
. . .人類的其他努力都顯得無足輕重。
Let's go, son. Move out!
開車走吧，小子。前進。
Give me that helmet, corporal.
把那頂鋼盔給我，下士。
Come on, let's get out of here!
走吧，我們離開這裡！
What silly son of a bitch is in charge of this operation?
哪個愚蠢的混蛋指揮這次作戰？
I don't know, but they ought to hang him.
我不知道，但是他們應該吊死他。
Good afternoon, Padre.
下午好，牧師。
General, these gentlemen are here from the States, looking over our program. . .
將軍，這些人從國內來考察我們部隊. . .
. . .for the spiritual welfare of the men's.
. . .官兵的精神生活狀況。
Good, take us, we'll take you right into Palermo.
好，緊跟住我們，我們會帶各位去巴勒莫
But Colonel David toured us around your quarters, gennral. . .
戴維斯上校帶我們參觀了你的寢室，將軍. . .
. . .pardon, and I was granted to see a Bible by your bed. You actually find time to read it?
. . .請原諒，經允許我在你床邊看到一部《聖經》，你真的有時間讀它嗎？
I sure do.
當然看。
Every goddamn day.
我他媽每天都看。
Sir, the Americans have taken Palermo!
長官，美軍已攻佔巴勒莫！
Damn!
該死！
Sir, Patton's taken Palermo!
長官，巴頓已攻佔巴勒莫！
Damn!
該死！
(CHEERING)
(BAND PLAYS)
Palermo's the most conquered city in history.
巴勒莫是史上易手最多的城市。
First the Phoenicians, . . .
起先是腓尼基人，. . .
. . .the Romans, Carthaginians, Byzantines, . . .
. . .羅馬人、迦太基人、拜占庭人，. . .
. . .then came the Arabs, . . .
. . .然後來的是阿拉伯人，. . .
. . .Spaniards, Neapolitans.
. . .西班牙人、那不勒斯人。
Now comes. . .
現在是. . .
. . .the American Army.
. . .美國陸軍。
This is from General Alexander, sir, . . .
這是亞歷山大將軍的命令，長官，. . .
. . .reminding you that you are not to take Palermo.
. . .提醒你不要攻佔巴勒莫。
Send him a message, Cod.
發通信給他，考德。
Ask him if he wants me to give it back.
問他要不要我還給德軍。
Well, Let me ask you a question for a change.
好了，換我來問各位問題。
You've just come from Washington.
各位剛從華盛頓來。
How do they feel about our boys taking Palermo?
各位對於我軍攻佔巴勒莫有什麼感想？
Well, sir, the general impression is, your 7th army barreled through token resistance. . .
這個嘛，將軍，一般的印象是，你的第七軍團只遇到了象徵性抵抗，. . .
. . .while Montgomery faced the brunt of the fighting.
. . .而蒙哥馬利在打硬仗。
My god, don't they know we took on the Hermann Geling division?
老天，他們難道不知道我們擊敗了赫爾曼·戈林師團？
Toughest outfit in the German Army.
那是德軍裝備最強硬的部隊。
Those people at home are interested in you, general.
國內人民對你感興趣，將軍。
They're curious about your pearl-handle revolvers.
他們對你的珍珠柄左輪手槍很好奇。
They're ivory. Only a pimp from a cheap New Orleans whorehouse would carry a pearl-handle pistol.
是象牙柄！只有新奧爾良妓院的皮條客才帶珍珠柄手槍！
What about your language, general?
你說的是粗話，將軍？
When I want it to stick, I give it to them loud and dirty. Then they will remember it.
當我要強調某事時我就大嗓門說髒話，這樣他們就會記住。
What do your troops feel about that, general.
這樣你的部下有何感想，將軍？
Goddamn, I don't want these men to love me. I want them to fight for me.
媽的，我不要他們愛我，我要他們為我戰鬥！
Ernie Pyle says you have a secret weapon here Sicily, General Bradley.
厄尼·派爾說你在西西里有一個秘密武器，布拉德利將軍。
"The G.I. General. " That's what Ernie calls him.
「平易近人的將軍」。厄尼這樣稱呼他。
Omar Bradley is no secret. He's a damn fine commander.
奧馬爾·布拉德利不是什麼秘密，他是一位非常優秀的軍官。
What's your feeling about Montgomery?
你對蒙哥馬利有何感想？
He's the best general the English have.
他是英國最好的將軍。
But "she" seems loaded more concerned with not losing battle than he does about winning one.
但「她」似乎更關心怎麼不打敗仗而不是怎麼去打勝仗。
He's not aggressive enough, is that correct?
他不夠積極，對嗎？
Look, boys, I've been getting into a lot of trouble lately.
啊，各位，我近來惹上很多麻煩。
Yesterday, the inspector general's office told me my Italian prisoners. . .
昨天，督察長辦公室告訴我，我的意大利戰俘. . .
. . .didn't have enough latrine.
. . .沒有足夠的廁所。
Hell, they didn't know what a damn latrine was till I showed them.
見鬼，我帶他們去看了之後，他們才知道什麼是軍廁。
If I've said anything too critical of my distinguished British colleague, . . .
如果我稍微批評了我傑出的英國同僚，. . .
. . .let's just forget about it, well?
. . .讓我們這就忘掉，好嗎？
I'll tell you one thing, though, off the record.
不過我可以告訴各位一件事，但不得報道。
I'm gonna beat that ... gentleman to Messina.
我會比那位 ... 紳士先到墨西拿。
巴頓誓取墨西拿以解救受挫的英國盟軍
Ah, Freddie. Do you realize what this madman Patton is saying?
啊，弗雷迪，你知道巴頓這個瘋子在說些什麼嗎？
He's going to save our skins by taking Messina.
他要攻佔墨西拿以解救我們。
This report might interest you, sir.
你可能對這篇報導感興趣，長官。
Here I am in these bloody marshes, fighting malaria and Germans, . . .
我在沼澤裡對抗虐疾與德軍，. . .
. . .while he's taking Palermo whitout opposing and getting all the glory.
. . .他卻未遭抵抗攻佔巴勒莫奪走了所有的光榮。
Ah, Well!
啊，好啊！
Now he's up against three good German divisions, and he's stuck for a change.
他現在面對三個師的優良德軍，輪到他受阻了。
He's not going to get Messina.
他不會攻佔墨西拿。
That is reserved for the British 8th Army and me.
那是保留給英國第八軍團和我的！
(BOMBS EXPLODING)
-It's time for a move, Lucian.
-Terry Allen's first Division is bogged down east of Torino.
該採取行動了，盧西恩。
泰瑞·艾倫的第一師在托裡諾以東受阻。
You're bogged down on the coast road.
你在海岸道路受阻。
What we need is another end run just to break things loose.
我們需要另一次迂迴，以打開困局。
-Lucian, how's my fighter?
-Fine, George.
盧西恩，我的勇士你好嗎？
還好，喬治。
Ah, Come in, come in. We need another one of your amphibious specialties.
啊，請進，請進，我們需要另一次兩棲登陸。
Ah, Lucian, I want you to send a reinforced battalion . . .
啊，盧西恩，我要你派一個加強營. . .
. . .by sea, to make a landing up here at Brolo behind the kraut lines.
. . .從海上，在德軍防線後面的巴羅洛登陸。
Gneeral Bradley says you want me tie this in with a land-based attack.
布拉德利將軍說你要我同時發動陸地上的進攻。
That's Right. I want a coordinated attack the morning of the 11th.
對，我要在11日早晨發動協同進攻。
I don't think we can make it by the 11th.
我不認為在11日能夠會師。
-Hell, it's only 15, 20 miles.
-General, but my boys have been fighting and dying for yards.
只有15或20英里而已！
將軍，我的部下每前進一碼都會戰死。
Well, . . .
喔，. . .
Maybe you better kick a few butts if you have to.
如果有必要，你或許應該多敦促部下加快進展。
Lucian, I recommended you for your DSM in your last promotion.
盧西恩，我推薦你獲得勳章以及上一次的晉陞。
I know what you can do when you put your mind to it.
我知道你盡心盡力去做能夠做到的事。
Excuse me, sir.
對不起，長官。
I'm sorry, but I can't do the impossible.
我很抱歉，但我無法做到不可能的事。
You're too old an athlete to think you can postpone a match it had already scheduled.
你是戰場老手，你不會亂想延後已經排定的事。
-You're an old athlete yourself, sir. You know matches sometimes are postponed.
-George.
你自己也是戰場老手，長官。你知道有時候也會延後。   喬治。
George, if Lucian is right, we can't back them up by land, our end run could be a disaster.
喬治，如果盧西恩沒說錯，我們無法在陸地支援他們，那我們的迂迴可能成為一場災難。
Uh, those men might get caught on the beach and cut to pieces.
那麼，那些部隊可能被困在海灘，而且會被消滅。
-What's the matter with you two?
-All we're talking about is not rushing in until we're ready.
你們兩個這是怎麼回事？
我們說只是沒準備好之前不要盲目推進。
Give them an extra day.
多給他們一天。
Just one more day.
只要多給一天。
The landing is on.
登陸要實施。
We're going to Messina.
我們要去墨西拿。
We're going to get there before Montgomery does.
我們要比蒙哥馬利先到那裡。
-What's so important about that?
-General Truscott, . . .
那有如此重要嗎？  特拉斯科特將軍，. . .
. . .if your conscience won't permit you to. . .
. . .如果你的良心不容許你. . .
. . .conduct this operation, I'll relieve you, and find somebody who can.
. . .進行這次作戰，我會撤換你，找能幹的人來做。
General, it's your privilege to relieve me anytime you want to.
將軍，你有權在任何時候撤換我。
Well, this match will not be postponed.
好了，這次作戰不會延後。
Do you have any questions?
你們還有什麼問題嗎？
No, sir.
沒有，長官。
You're a very good man, Lucian.
你是很好的軍官，盧西恩。
You want to guard against being too conservative.
但你要慎防過度保守。
Remember what Frederick the Great said, . . .
記住弗雷德裡克大帝說的那句偉大的話：. . .
. . .''L 'audace, l'audace! Toujours l'audace!''
. . .「大膽，大膽！永遠大膽！」
Go on, have a drink.
來吧，喝一杯。
Excuse me, sir, I won't be drinking for the next couple of days.
對不起，長官，我接下來的幾天都不喝酒。
If anything happens to those men, I'd like to be there with them.
如果部下遭遇苦戰，我要與他們在一起。
Well, you're not going, so forget about it.
啊，你可不是要去，那就免談。
You believe Truscott's right, huh?
你認為特拉斯科特說的對, 嗯？
No.
不。
But I do know you're gambling with the lives of those boys just so you can beat Montgomery into Messina.
但是我的確知道，你在用部下的生命作賭注以便你比蒙哥馬利先拿下墨西拿。
And if you pull it off, you're a big hero, but if you don't, . . .
如果你賭贏了，你就是大英雄，但如果你賭輸了，. . .
What happens to them, your ordinary combat soldier?
你想過部下會有什麼遭遇嗎？你的那些普通的戰士？
He doesn't share in your dreams of glory, he's stuck here.
他們無法分享你的榮耀之夢，他們會被困死在這裡。
He's stuck living out every day, day-to-day, with death tugging at his elbow.
他們每天困在與死神擦身而過的日子。
There's one big difference between you and me, George.
你我有一點大不相同，喬治。
I do this job because I've been trained to do it.
我打仗是因為他們訓練我去打仗。
You do it because. . .
而你打仗是因為. . .
. . .you love it.
. . .你熱愛打仗。
Those men on the beach are catching hell, general.
海灘上的部隊真的很慘，將軍。
Truscott's men are doing their best, but we have no replacements for them.
特拉斯科特的部下正在竭盡全力，但我們沒有補充兵源給他們。
We can't break through to the coast.
我們無法突破到海岸。
I'm going down there myself.
我要親自去那邊。
Colonel!
中校！
How in the hell did he get over there?
他是怎麼到那邊去的？
What the hell are you waiting for?
你還在等什麼？
Looking for a place here that's a ford, general.
正在這裡找尋徒涉點，將軍。
I sent out a patrol to reconnoiter.
我正派巡邏隊去偵察。
I've already done that. Right down there this sewer's no more than 3 feet deep.
我已偵察過了，就在那邊，這條水溝不到三英尺深。
You get that outfit cranked up or you'll be out of a job!
你的部隊立即行動，否則就撤你的職！
-And put that helmet on!
-Yes, sir.
戴上鋼盔！  是，長官。
Move it! Let's go!
開動坦克！前進！
-What's holding up this column?
-I don't know, sir.
這個縱隊為何停下來？  我不知道，長官。
Planes!
敵機！
Come on! move it!
趕快！前進！
Pull up over there.
靠邊停車。
-These mules, here.   Come on!
-What's going on here?
這些騾子，這兒。  走啊！  這裡怎麼回事？
Sir, these mules!
長官，是這些騾子！
Jackasses!
混蛋！
You hold up a column get stalled and strafed on account of two jackasses?
你讓整個縱隊停下來挨揍，就是為了兩頭笨騾？
That's what the hell's the matter with you?!
這都是你幹的好事？！
(GUNSHOT)
No. No.
不，不。
Now, dump them over the side and clear this bridge!
趕快，把它們從橋邊丟下去，清理橋面！
Now, the reson we're pinned down, general, because we can't get air support!
現在我們前進受阻，將軍，是因為沒有空中支援。
Hell nobody is! Nobody's getting any air support!
胡扯！沒人得到過空中支援！
You can put fire into this battalion, colonel, or I'll get somebody who can.
要麼你鼓動起這個營，中校，要麼我就找能夠的人來做。
Major!
少校！
-You the executive officer here?
-Yes, sir.
你是副營長嗎？  是的，長官。
-What's your name?
-Walker, sir.
-你姓什麼？  -沃克，長官。
You're now the commanding officer.
你現在是該營營長了。
You've got 4 hours to break through to that beachhead down here.
你得在4小時內，突破到下面的海灘。
If you don't make it, I'll fire you.
如果到時候沒做到，我就撤換你。
Colonel, there are 50,000 men on this island would like to shoot that son of a bitch.
中校，這個島上有五萬人都想開槍斃了那個狗娘養的。
Please take me home. Take me home.
拜託送我回家，送我回家。
-There he goes, "Old Blood and Guts. "
-Yeah, our blood, his is guts.
「血膽老爹」走了。  用我們的血，換來他的大膽。
Hi, how are you, son?
嗨，還好嗎，孩子？
Where are you from, uh, Gomez?
你是哪裡人，啊，高梅茲？
California, sir.
加利福尼亞，長官。
Me too.
我也是。
-Where were you hit?
-In the chest, sir.
你哪裡中彈？  胸部，長官。
Well, . . .
哦，. . .
. . .this might be interesting to you. The last German I saw didn't have any chest.
. . .你可能會覺得有意思。我剛才看到的德軍沒有胸部。
Didn't have any head, either.
連頭也沒有。
You get well quickly, son.
祝你早日康復，小子！
What's the matter with you?
你有什麼問題？
I guess ... I just can't take it, sir.
我猜 ... 我實在受不了了。
What did you say?
你說什麼？
It's my nerves, sir.
我的神經有問題，長官。
I just can't stand the shelling anymore.
我實在受不了炮轟了。
Your nerves?
你的神經？
Hell, you're just a goddamn coward.
扯蛋，你只是個該死的懦夫！
Shut up!
閉嘴！
I won't have a yellow bastard crying in front of these brave men who've been wounded in battle.
我不准懦夫在此哭泣當著戰鬥中負傷的勇士面前。
Shut up!
閉嘴！
Don't admit this yellow bastard. There's nothing wrong with him.
不准這個混蛋住院！他根本沒問題。
I won't have sons of bitches who are afraid to fight stinking up this place of honor.
我不准狗娘養的懦夫養玷污了這個光榮的地方。
You're going back to the front, my friend.
你必須回前線，朋友。
You may get shot, you may get killed, but you're going up to the fighting, . . .
你可能中槍，你可能喪生，但你必須去作戰，. . .
. . .you don't, either that or I'll stand you up in front of a firing squad.
. . .你不作戰，我就派行刑隊槍斃你。
I ought to shoot you myself, you goddamn crying bastard! Get him out of here!
我應該親自槍斃你，你這個該死的愛哭鬼！把他拉出去！
Send him up to the front!
把他送到前線去！
You hear me? You goddamn coward!
你聽見了嗎？你這該死的懦夫！
I won't have cowards in my army.
我的部隊容不下懦夫！
I had to kick a few butts up there, but, uh, Truscott finally broke through to those people on the beach.
有時侯，我必須要得罪某些人，不過，啊，特拉斯科特終於突破後抵達海灘會師了。
Have you seen the casualty lists?
你看過傷亡名單嗎？
Yes, I've seen them.
是的，我看過了。
What's the word from the coast road?
海岸公路有消息嗎？
Well, the 3rd Division's east of Brolo, heading toward Messina.
喔，第三師位於巴羅洛以東，正在向墨西拿前進。
Well, Let's get drives over there. I want to go in with the troops.
好的，讓我們趕過去，我想穿戴整齊與部隊一起進城。
You go ahead, George. I'm not very good at that.
你先去吧，喬治。我不善於那種事。
General Bradley, . . .
布拉德利將軍，. . .
. . .it's time to consider how many casualties we'd have. . .
. . .現在應該考慮，會有多大的傷亡. . .
. . .if we were still down there crawling along that goddamn road.
. . .如果我們現在還在那條見鬼的道路上緩慢前進的話。
Forward ... , march!
齊步 ... 走！
Don't smirk, Patton. I shan't kiss you.
別傻笑，巴頓。我不會吻你的。
Pity. I shaved very close this morning in preparation for getting smacked by you.
真可惜，我今早刮臉細刮得特別乾淨，就等著你吻我呢。
Forward ... , march!
齊步 ... 走！
You wanted to see me, George?
你要見我，喬治？
I got a letter here from Ike.
我收到一封艾克的信。
I, uh, . . .
我，啊，. . .
I was re-reading Caesar's Commentaries last night.
我昨晚在重讀凱撒的評傳。
In battle, Caesar wore a red robe to distinguish him from his men.
在戰鬥時，凱撒穿紅袍以區別他與部下。
I was struck by that fact because. . .
我震驚於那個事實，因為. . .
"Despicable. " That's the first time my life anybody ever applied that word to me.
「可恥。」我這輩子第一次有人用那個字來形容我。
Well, at least it's a personal reprimand, it's not official.
不過，至少那只是個人責備，而不是官方的。
The man was yellow. He should've been tried for cowardice and shot.
那個人是個懦夫！他應該接受軍事審判而且被槍斃！
My god! Have we forgotten about those people take have a lot worse than a little kick in the pants.
老天！難道他們忘了那些遭遇比被責罵更慘的人？
I ruffled his pride a bit. What's that compared to war?
我只是稍微損及他的自尊，但那與戰爭相比算什麼？
Two weeks ago, we took Palermo, . . .
兩周前我們攻佔巴勒莫時，. . .
they call me a hero, they said I was the greatest general since Stonewall Jackson.
他們稱我是自「石牆」傑克遜以來最偉大的將軍。
And now they draw cartoons about you.
而現在，他們卻畫漫畫來諷刺你。
Dirty bastard!
臭狗屎！
They got me holding a little Gl and kicking him with an iron boot.
他們畫我抓著小兵而且用鐵靴子踢他。
You see that, what's on my boot? A swastika.
你看到了嗎，我靴子上是什麼？納粹標記！
On my boot. An iron boot with a swastika!
在我靴子上！有納粹標記的鐵靴子！
"You will apologize to the soldier you slapped, . . .
你應該向你打耳光的士兵道歉，. . .
. . .to all doctors and nurses who were present in the tent at the time, . . .
. . .還有當時在帳蓬裡的所有的醫官與護士，. . .
. . .to every patient in the tent who can be reached, . . .
. . .還有在帳蓬裡的每一個能夠來的傷病員，. . .
. . .and last but not least to the 7th Army as a whole, . . .
. . .最後向第七軍團全體，. . .
. . .through individual units, one at a time. "
. . .依次向每一個連隊道歉！
God, I. . .
老天！我. . .
. . .feel low.
. . .情緒真的很低落。
Oh, God, . . .
啊，神啊，. . .
. . . Thou art my God.
. . .你是我的神。
Verily will I seek Thee.
我虔誠地搜尋你。
My soul thirsteth for Thee.
我的靈魂渴望著你。
My flesh longeth for Thee in a dry and thirsty land, . . .
我的肉體在乾渴之土地上期盼著你，. . .
. . .so as I have seen Thee in the sanctuary.
. . .只要我在聖殿裡看見你。
My soul followeth hard after Thee.
我的靈魂努力地追尋著你。
But those that seek my soul to destroy it. . .
那些想要摧毀我靈魂的人. . .
. . .shall go into the lower parts of the earth.
. . .應該進入十八層地獄。
They shall fall by the sword.
他們將死於刀劍之下。
They shall be apportioned for foxes.
他們將被狐貍分食。
But the king shall rejoice in God.
但是強者樂於信奉神靈。
Everyone that sweareth by him shall glory.
每個發誓維護真理的人將獲得榮耀。
But the mouth of them that speak lies. . .
那些說謊的嘴. . .
. . .shall be stopped.
. . .將被封住。
Ten ... hut!
立 ... 正！
At ease.
稍息。
I thought I would stand up here and let you people see, . . .
我想我應該站在這裡讓各位看看，. . .
. . .if I am as big a son of a bitch as some of you think I am.
. . .我是不是一個大混蛋，像你們有些人想的那樣。
I assure you I had no intention. . .
我向各位保證我絕不是有意要. . .
. . .of being either harsh or cruel in my treatment of the. . .
. . .以粗暴或殘酷方式來對待. . .
. . .soldier in question.
. . .那位士兵的。
My sole purpose was to try to restore in him some appreciation of his obligations as a man. . .
我唯一的目的是試圖讓他重新認識他的責任和應盡的義務，作為一個人. . .
. . .and as a soldier.
. . .和作為一個軍人。
If one can shame a coward, I felt, . . .
如果一個人以懦弱為恥，我覺得，. . .
. . .one might help him to regain his self-respect.
. . .這可以幫助他重新獲得自尊。
This was on my mind.
我當時就是這麼想的。
Now, I freely admit. . .
現在，我誠懇地承認. . .
. . .that my method was wrong.
. . .我的做法是錯誤的。
But I hope you understand my motive, . . .
但我希望各位能理解我的動機，. . .
. . .and will accept this. . .
. . .而且接受. . .
. . .explanation, . . .
. . .我的解釋，. . .
. . .and this. . .
. . .和我的. . .
. . .apology.
. . .道歉。
-Dismissed.
-Ten ... hut!
解散。  立 ... 正！
Good evening, general. Just one, I make a report on a private poll I've been taking.
將軍，晚安！就一件小事，我報告一下我自己做的一次民意調查。
What poll?
什麼民意調查？
The fan mail.
各界來信。
11 percent con, 89 percent pro.
11% 反對，89% 支持
And that 11% of protest, in most cases, is both obscene and anonymous.
那些反對的 11% 大都是猥褻和匿名。
But the pro letters are mostly from relatives and servicemen.
但是支持者大部份是親屬與軍人。
"I want you to know we're proud our son is serving in your army.
我們想讓您知道我們以兒子在您的部隊服役為榮。
From the newspaper accounts, we're not clear exactly what you did and why, ...
我們從報紙的敘述中，不清楚您究竟做了什麼、為何這麼做，...
. . .but we want you to know we're for you.
. . .但我們希望您知道我們支持您。
Keep going, and God bless you. "
繼續前進，願上帝保佑您。
Keep going, huh?
繼續前進，那是？
Where?
去哪裡？
I thought you might like a sip of wine, general. It's New Year's.
我想您可能想小酌，將軍。現在是新年了。
You didn't celebrate at all last night.
您昨晚完全沒有慶祝。
I'm sick of sitting around this ... royal doghouse.
我討厭蹲在這個 ...皇家狗屋裡。
We've taken Sicily. I'm ready for a new assignment.
我們已攻佔西西里。我已準備接受新任務。
Well, maybe you've got it. Here's a radio message, just came in.
啊，或許您已經得到了。這是剛到的電報。
Cod, . . .
考德，. . .
I've been relieved.
我被解除職務了。
They've relieved me from command of the 7th Army.
他們解除我指揮第七軍團的職務。
I don't believe it.
我不相信。
Happy New Year.
新年快樂。
Just a minute, sir.
等一等，長官。
Since they're sure to give you another command, . . .
因為他們必定會給你別的指揮職務，. . .
. . .isn't it logical that they'd relieve you here first?
. . .他們得先解除你在這兒的職務，這豈不是合乎邏輯？
You mean, command of all American troops going into Europe?
你是說，指揮進入歐洲的全部美軍部隊？
It's possible by a idea. I know it's been discussed from time to time.
這倒是種可能性。我知道不時有人在討論這件事。
The logic of it is so obvious, it couldn't mean anything else.
其中的邏輯非常明顯，不可能有其他的事。
Sir, I'm going to open this bottle of wine.
長官，我要打開這瓶酒。
No, Sir Cod. . .
不，考德先生. . .
. . .but if you find a bottle of cognac, and karat bottle, I'll help you drink it.
. . .但如果你能找到一瓶干邑（法國產世界名酒），而且開瓶，我就幫你喝掉它。
-How are you feeling tonight, general?
-Not bad, not bad at all.
您今晚覺得如何，將軍？  不錯，很不錯。
-Get me some writing paper, would you?
-Yes, sir.
給我拿一些信紙，好嗎？  好的，長官。
Your wife ever give you the devil for not writing?
你太太罵過你不寫信嗎？
All the time, sir.
隨時都罵，長官。
Only I don't write as often as you do. Don't seem to get around to it.
但我不像您寫得那麼勤。我似乎沒時間寫信。
Lucky thing for us we've got them.
我們有妻子真幸運，對嗎？
Who wants to marry a couple of broken-down old horse captains?
誰肯嫁兩個老骨頭騎兵？
That's what my wife says to me everytime I come home, sir.
我每次回家我太太都對我那樣說，長官。
Why are you doing up so late, George?
你為何這麼晚還沒睡，喬治？
Just thought you might like a nice hot bath, glass of milk or something.
只是猜想您可能想要洗一個舒適的熱水浴、或者喝一杯牛奶之類的。
I got you sleeping pill from the doc, just in case you might need them.
長官，我向醫官拿了安眠藥，以備您需要它。
Sleeping pill!
安眠藥！
-What's going on here anyway?
-We all heard the news announced, sir.
究竟怎麼回事？  我們都聽了今晚的新聞，長官。
-They announced it on the radio.
-What news?
他們在廣播裡宣佈的。  什麼新聞？
About General Bradley, sir.
關於布拉德利將軍，長官。
How they gave him the top American command for the invasion.
他們任命他為進攻歐洲的美軍最高指揮官。
Oh.
噢。
Oh, yeah.
噢，好的。
I, well, but, I just thought you might be feeling kind of low, sir.
我，啊，這個，我以為您可能會感覺情緒低落，長官。
Your writing things, sir, here on the desk, sir.
您的書寫用品，長官，都放在桌上，長官。
Yeah. Thank you, George.
好的。謝謝你，喬治！
One little dogface.
都因一個小兵。
One measly little slap. That's what done it.
一記小兵的耳光。就是那件事給害的。
Ah, George.
噢，喬治。
I wish I'd kissed the son of a bitch.
我真希望我願意親吻了那個狗娘養的。
（中場間斷）
(CLAPPING)
科西嘉島 阿雅克修
(PATTON SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
我們向戴高樂將軍與雷克勒克將軍領導的
自由法國的優秀部隊致敬
He's paying tribute to the Free French Forces under De-Gaulle and Leclerc.
他在向戴高樂與雷克勒克麾下的自由法國軍隊致敬。
(SPEAKS IN FRENCH)
（法語）
Also to the brave men and women of the Resistance who risked their lives everyday to help to destroy the Germans.
也向地下抵抗軍的英勇男女致敬，他們冒著生命危險幫助摧毀德軍。
（法語）
"France will be free again. I give you my word. "
法蘭西將恢復自由，我向各位保證。
（法語）
"Just as Free French troops landed here in Corsica to liberate the birthplace of Napoleon's, . . .
就像法國部隊登陸科西嘉解放拿破侖的故鄉一樣，. . .
. . .I will someday land in France to help liberate the birthplace of Lafayette. "
. . .我將在法國登陸，以幫助解放拉法葉的故鄉。
General, the reporters would like a word with you.
將軍，記者想採訪您。
-Good afternoon, gentlemen.
-General!
下午好，各位。  將軍！
General Patton, can you tell us the purpose of this visit to Corsica?
巴頓將軍，能告訴我們你訪問科西嘉的目的嗎？
I was ordered at here by General Eisenhower.
我奉艾森豪威爾將軍之命來到這裡。
It was reported, you wrote the mother of the boy slapped and saying: "The yellow rat should've been shot."
據說你寫信給被打耳光的士兵的母親說：「膽小鼠輩應該被槍斃。」
-Is that true, general?
-No comment.
是真的嗎，將軍？  無可奉告。
Sir, I understand General Alexander suggested you take over General Clark's Italian campaign, . . .
將軍，據說亞歷山大將軍建議你接手馬克·克拉克將軍的意大利戰役，. . .
. . .but what common killed that because the slapping incident.
. . .但因為耳光事件該建議被否決了。
-No comment.
-Can you tell a say where you're going, sir?
無可奉告。  您能談談要去何處嗎，將軍？
General Eisenhower's ordered me to Malta. That's Off the record.
艾森豪威爾將軍命令我去馬耳他，但這不能報導。
Interview concluded.
訪談結束。
You plan on slapping any soldiers there, general?
您還打算在那裡打士兵的耳光嗎，將軍？
什麼？
Malta?
馬耳他？
Yes, sir.
是的，長官。
Malta as a base, . . .
馬耳他當作基地，. . .
. . .then southern Greece.That is possible.
. . .然後是希臘南部，那是有可能的。
Get me Field Marshal Keitel.
給我接凱爾元帥。
In 1528, these forts were defended by 400 Knights of Malta and 800 mercenaries. . .
在1528年，這些城堡由400名馬耳他武士與800名傭兵防守，. . .
. . .against a force of 40,000 Turks.
. . .對抗四萬土耳其人。
Oh, well, Codman.
喔，啊，考德曼。
-Still no word from Gen. Eisenhower?
-No, sir.
有艾森豪威爾將軍的消息嗎？  長官，沒有
Not even a response about, uh, the two turkeys I sent for Christmas?
甚至沒有對，啊，我聖誕節送他的兩隻火雞有反應嗎？
No, sir.
沒有，將軍。
Uh, Go ahead, gentlemen. Take careful a closer look for yourselves.
喔，各位，請自己過去仔細看看。
Well, Looks like you boys have hitched your wagon to a falling star.
哎，看來各位是跟錯了長官。
Pass the word. If anybody wants out, I'll understand.
傳話下去，如果有人要離開，我會理解的。
Sir, I can speak for the entire staff.
長官，我可以代表全體參謀發言。
We want to stay with you, no matter what duty you're assigned to.
不管您被指派什麼任務，我們都會追隨您。
Up in London, they're planning the invasion of Europe.
他們在倫敦計劃進攻歐洲。
That's what I've trained my whole mind, body, and spirit for.
我整個身心都是為了那個而時刻準備著。
What in God's name, am I doing here?
上帝，我究竟在這裡做什麼？
All right.
好吧。
Let's get on to Cairo.
我們去開羅。
See if the pyramids are still standing.
看看金字塔還在不在。
There is only one reason for him to be in Cairo.
他去開羅只有一個原因，
To confer with the Greek and Yugoslav governments in exile.
去和希臘和與南斯拉夫的流亡政府開會。
Let the Italians garrison Italy,it's their country.
讓意大利人防守意大利。那是他們的國家。
We'll need our German troops to reinforce Crete and the Greek coast if Patton strikes from Egypt!
我們需要德軍增援克里特與希臘海岸以防巴頓從埃及出擊！
I have some new information, sir.
我有新消息，長官。
Patton is under severe criticism. He may even be court-martialed.
巴頓遭到嚴重批評。他甚至可能接受軍事法庭審訊。
He slapped an enlisted man.
因為他打了士兵一記耳光。
You believe their newspapers?
你相信他們的報紙？
Would they sacrifice their best commander because he slapped a soldier?
他們會犧牲他們最好的將領，就因為他打了士兵的耳光？
倫敦
-This place is for me?
-Yes, sir. This way, sir.
讓我住這兒？  是的，長官，這邊請。
Whoever found it has a genius for cloak-and-dagger.
找到這裡的人是個優秀的陰謀家。
Who picked this cathouse?
是誰找到這個妓院的？
I believe it was General Smith, sir.
我想是史密斯將軍，長官。
He use it to spite me, that son of a bitch.
那個狗娘養的想要用這來羞辱我。
-Welcome to London, Georgie.
-Bedell. How are you?
歡迎來到倫敦，喬治。
畢托，你好嗎？
-Is Ike here?
-He asked me to brief you.
艾克在倫敦嗎？
他要我對你作簡報。
Do you excuse us, please?
你們能迴避一下嗎？
First let me put you straight about Ike.
首先讓我糾正你關於艾克的事。
We hear a lot about you criticizing his decisions.
我們時常聽說你批評他的決策。
No, not really. You know me. I'm just an old fool.
不，那不是真的。你瞭解我，我只是個老傻瓜。
Sometimes, I do wonder whether he isn't a limey at heart.
我有時候真的挺納悶，他內心裡是不是一個英國佬。
George, this is the toughest coalition ever attempted in history.
喬治，這是歷史上最困難的聯盟。
Ike sits it upon, trying to hold it together and lick the Germans at the same time.
艾克坐在上面，企圖維持聯盟，同時痛擊德軍。
-Now believe me, It's one hell of a job.
-I appreciate that.
請相信我，這是很困難的事。
我能理解那回事。
Now, we have an important assignment for you in connected to the Normandy invasion.
現在，我們有關於諾曼底登陸很重要的任務交給你。
Good. I've studied the Overlord Plan and there's a number of flaws in it.
好！我研究過「霸王」計劃，它有幾處瑕疵。
Not the least which it is dependency on Monty taking Cannes by D-day. He'll never make it.
你至少不要指靠蒙蒂在D日攻佔戛納。他絕對做不到。
I've drawn up an alternate plan as call for land at Calais. . .
我擬定一個替代計劃，在登陸加萊. . .
-. . .following an air bombardment. . .
-Please, would you just listen for a change?
. . .在進行轟炸之後. . .
拜託，你就不能聽別人一次嗎？
Remember, Ike stood by you when everyone, I mean everyone wanted Patton with a rope around his neck.
記住，艾克支持你，然而人人，我是說人人都想吊死巴頓！
We're gonna let it leak out that you are here undercover.
我們會洩露你暗中來到倫敦。
That you're preparing to invade at the Pas de Calais.
說你計劃入侵加萊。
We hope to pin down the German 15th Army there so that they can't be used against us at Normandy.
我們想釘住那裡的德軍第十五軍團使他們無法用在諾曼底對抗我軍。
That's all your pepole think I'm good for?
你們就認為我只有那個用處嗎？
We're going to build an army of 12 divisions around you.
我們將圍繞你建立有12個師的集團軍。
All fictitious, of course.
全都是虛擬的，當然。
Dummy troop concentrations, dummy landing craft, simulated radio traffic.
假的部隊集結，假的登陸艇，模擬的無線電通信。
The see, the Germans are convinced that you are going to lead the main invasion effort.
是的，德軍堅信你將領導主要的入侵。
Their agents will spot you here, before then we can move you to new headquarters Knutsford.
他們的間諜很快就會發現你在這裡，然後我們會把你移到在諾斯福的新總部。
-What do I do there?
-Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
我在那裡做什麼？  什麼也不做！
Frankly, George, you're on probation.
坦白地說，喬治，你被留職察看了。
You take my advice, you'll behave yourself.
如果你聽我的勸，就該約束自己的言行。
Remember, . . .
記住，. . .
. . .your worst enemy is your own big mouth.
. . .你最大的敵人就是你口無遮攔。
(BAND PLAYS)
Look at this nasty-faced son of a bitch. Ready for combat.
考德曼，看這面目猙獰的狗狗崽子。為戰鬥而生。
I'm calling him William, "William the Conqueror".
我要叫它威廉，征服者威廉。
-General, maybe we ought to leave him in the car?
-No, sorry. Good afternoon, ladies.
將軍，或許我們應該把它留在車子裡？
不用，沒事的。下午好，女士們！
Good afternoon.
下午好！
(WlLLlE BARKS)
Watch this, Cod.
注意，考德。
-General, he'll kill that dog.
-No, he won't.
將軍，它會吃掉那隻狗的。  不會，它不會的。
I'm terribly sorry, general. Did Abigail frighten your dog?
我極為抱歉，將軍！阿比蓋爾嚇到您的狗了嗎？
That's quite all right, madam.
沒什麼，女士。
This way, sir.
這邊走，將軍。
Your name isn't William.
看來你不該叫「威廉」。
It's Willie.
你該叫「婉莉」。
My dear friends.
親愛的朋友們。
General George S. Patton, Jr., has accepted our invitation. . .
小喬治·史密斯·巴頓將軍，接受我們的邀來此. . .
. . .to say a few words to you. . .
. . .為我們講幾句話，. . .
. . .on the occasion of this inaugural ceremony.
. . .在這次民間舉辦的聚會上。
General Patton is not here in an official capacity, . . .
巴頓將軍不是官方的身份發言，
. . .and I have assured him most earnestly. . .
. . .我以最誠懇的態度向他保證，. . .
. . .that nothing he says will be quoted.
. . .他說的話都不會被引用。
May I present ... General Patton.
我向各位介紹 ... 巴頓將軍
-Remember, sir, watch your language.
-Mmm, yeah.
記住，長官，注意措辭。  嗯，是的。
Ah, my dear ladies.
啊，親愛的女士們。
Until today. . .
直到今天為止，. . .
. . .my only experience at welcoming. . .
. . .我經歷過的唯一歡迎儀式，. . .
. . . has been to welcome Germans and Italians to the infernal region.
. . .是歡迎德國人與意大利人進入十八層地獄。
At this I have been quite successful. . .
在這方面我做的很成功. . .
. . .since the troops, which I have had the honor to command. . .
. . .因為我有幸指揮的部隊，. . .
. . .have to date, killed or captured. . .
. . .至今為止已殺死和俘獲了. . .
. . .some 170,000 of our enemies.
. . .大約17萬敵軍。
I feel that such clubs as these are of very real value, . . .
我覺得這樣的俱樂部很有價值，. . .
. . .because I believe with Mr. Bernard Shaw. . .
. . .因為我相信肖伯納所說的. . .
. . .that the British and the Americans are two peoples. . .
. . .英國人與美國人是兩個. . .
. . .separated by a common language.
. . .被一種共同的語言所隔離的民族。
And since it is the evident destiny of the British and Americans to rule the world, . . .
既然英美人民的歷史使命就是統治世界，. . .
. . .the better we know each other, . . .
. . .我們越是互相瞭解，. . .
. . .the better we will do it.
. . .我們就會做得越好。
The Russians. Don't forget the Russians.
俄國人！別忘了俄國人。
I think that a club like this is an ideal place for promoting mutual understanding.
我認為，像這樣的俱樂部是促進相互瞭解的理想之地。
Because, uh, as soon as our soldiers meet and get to know the English ladies, . . .
因為，啊，一旦我們的士兵結識了英國女士，. . .
. . .and write home and tell our women just how lovely you truly are, . . .
. . .而且寫信告訴美國婦女各位是多麼地可愛，. . .
. . .then the sooner the American ladies will get jealous, . . .
. . .那麼，美國女士一旦吃醋，. . .
. . .and force this war to a quick termination.
. . .就會逼著這場戰爭早日結束。
And then I'll get the chance to go to the Pacific and kill Japanese.
然後，我就有機會去太平洋殺日本人了。
巴頓侮辱俄國盟友！
In cities all over the nation. . .
全美各大城市的. . .
...mass meetings are held to protest General Patton 's statement, ...
...群眾集會抗議巴頓將軍所發表的言論，...
...that Britain and America will rule the postwar world, ...
...說英美將統治戰後的世界，...
...that Russia will have nothing to say.
...俄國將沒有發言權。
Congressional leaders like Senator Clayburn Foss are quick to react.
如同福斯參議員那樣的國會領袖迅速反應。
This man has insulted our Russian allies, . . .
此人侮辱了我們的俄國盟友，. . .
. . .implying Anglo-American world rule.
. . .他暗示英美將統治世界。
And in my opinion, he should be severely disciplined.
依我看來，他應該受到嚴厲的懲罰。
None, no, Bedell. This time I didn't do a damn thing.
沒有，不，畢托，這次我什麼也沒做。
They promised me they wouldn't be any reporters there.
他們向我保證那裡沒有記者。
Also I did adlibitum made a few remarks off the record.
因此，我可以即興講演隨意說幾句，而不被報道。
Ike told you to keep your mouth shut. You won't listen.
艾克要你閉嘴，你就是不聽。
Don't you reallies how suspicious the Russians are of the British and us.
難道你真的不知道俄國人對英美有多麼懷疑嗎？
I was only trying to be polite to the old ladies.
我只是試圖對那些老太太有禮貌。
If there'd been any Russians there, I would have mentioned them.
如果我看見那裡有俄國人，我就會提到他們。
I don't like the sons of bitches, but I would have mentioned them out of politeness.
我不喜歡那些狗娘養的，但我會禮貌地提到他們。
Bedell, I don't know anything about politics, ... you know that.
畢托，我完全不懂政治 ... 你是知道的。
I have no political ambitions afterwar. All I want to do is command an army in combat.
我在戰後沒有政治野心。我只是想指揮部隊作戰！
Well, it's out of our hands, now.
算了，我現在已經控制不住了。
Ike sent a message last night to the chief of staff.
艾克昨晚送消息給了參謀總長。
So now it's up to General Marshall will decide whether you stay here as a decoy or. . .
因此現在要看馬歇爾將軍的意思了，是讓你留下繼續扮誘餌還是. . .
. . .he sends you home.
. . .送你回國。
Well, He's a good man.
好吧，他是個好人。
At least he's a fair man.
至少他是個公正的人。
I'll let it sit with him.
就讓他決定好了。
George, . . .
喬治，. . .
. . .our war is over.
. . .我們的戰爭結束了。
Over, sir?
結束了，長官？
It's just a question of waiting for the orders now.
現在只是等命令而已。
I feel I, . . . .
我覺得我，. . .
. . .am destined to achieve some great thing. What, I don't know.
. . .注定要完成天降大任，但我說不清楚是什麼事情。
But this last incident is so . . .
最近的這些雞毛蒜皮的事情，. . .
. . .trivial in its nature and so terrible in its effect. It. . .
. . .原本微不足道，但影響可怕。這. . .
. . .(It) can't be the result of an accident. It has to be the work of God.
. . .(這)不可能只是意外，這一定是神靈的旨意。
Yes, sir.
是的，長官。
The last great opportunity of a lifetime. . . .
這是我畢生最後的偉大機會。. . .
. . .An entire world at war and I'm left out of it?
. . .全世界都在打仗，而我卻在袖手旁觀？
No, sir.
不會的，長官。
God will not permit this to happen!
上帝怎能允許這種事情發生！
I am going to be allowed to fulfil my destiny!
我必將會實現我的命運！
His will be done.
神靈將會幫助我實現。
D日！盟軍反攻法國！
In the greatest amphibious operation ever attempted, ...
在史上最大的兩棲作戰中，...
...a predawn naval bombardment prepares the way...
...黎明前的轟炸準備為...
...for Allied soldiers to assault the Normandy beaches, ...
...盟軍在諾曼底搶灘登陸，...
...and claw out a desperate foothold on the continent of Europe.
...並且在歐洲大陸取得立足點。
《諾曼底征服史》
I knew Montgomery couldn't take Caen on D-day or D-plus-10, and I said so.
我就知道蒙蒂無法在D日或其後10天攻佔戛納，我早就說過。
And here they are all hung up in the hedgerow country.
他們現在全困在樹籬地區。
But they should now, ah, pivot the way von Schlieffen planned it in World War I.
他們現應該折回向希里芬，像在第一次世界大戰中計劃的一樣。(First World War)
Then we might get a chance to do some real broken-field running.
然後我們可能有機會進行真正的山地運動。
But they don't listen to me.
但他們不聽我的話。
Huh, what a way to enter the continent of Europe, . . .
嗯，這樣進入歐洲真稀罕，. . .
. . .along with all the rest of the spare parts.
. . .和一大批備用零件一起。
Sir, everything on this plane is high priority.
長官，這架飛機上每件東西都是最高優先級的。
General Bradley wouldn't send for you unless he had something in mind.
除非他心裡有數，否則布拉德利將軍不會召您來的。
I'll tell you, Cod. I've learned my lesson.
聽我說，考德，我已經學乖了。
If I ever do get another chance, I'm gonna keep my mouth shut.
如果我得到機會，我會緊緊閉上我的嘴巴。
I'm gonna play the game.
我會玩官場那一套。
If I forget, you remind me.
如果我忘了，你就提醒我。
-I'll give a gentle nudge in the ribs.
-Give me a swift kick in the ass.
我會用胳膊輕輕碰您一下。
你應該用力朝屁股上踹我一腳！
Yes, sir.
遵命，長官！
Gennral. Welcome to France, sir.
將軍。歡迎來到法國，長官！
I hope the war's still on, Hansen. Where's the boss?
我希望戰爭還在進行中，漢森。老闆在哪裡？
Right this way, sir.
這邊請，長官。
第一軍團司令部
-Patton, haven't seen you since Messina.
-General, how are you?
巴頓，從墨西拿一別後還沒看到過你。
將軍，你好嗎？
I heard you're doing a splendid job decoying the Jerries.
我聽說你欺騙德軍做得極為成功。
Well, you'll forgive me, I'm off for the front.
好了，請你多包涵，我要去前線了。
Best of everything, old boy.
祝一切順利，老小子。
By the way, . . .
順便提一句，. . .
. . .intelligence confirms that I'm against Rommel again.
. . .情報證實我將再度對峙隆美爾。
Rommel!?
隆美爾！？
Hi, how are you, George?
嗨，你好嗎，喬治？
-Pretty fair, Brad. How are you?
-Fine.
我還不錯，布拉德。你好嗎？
還好。
Well, my, my. Isn't this plush?
你瞧瞧，我來這裡。是不是很豪華？
It looks like you're bucking for archbishop.
看來你在爭取大主教職位。
Well, Chet Hansen had this rig built for me. George, sit down.
啊，這是漢森為我訂製的。喬治，請坐。
Ike wanted me to talk to you.
艾克要我和你談談。
I told Ike you and I could level with each other.
我告訴他你我之間可以有話直說。
That's right.
是的。
We're going to make 3rd Army operational once that I take over 12th Army group.
一旦我接掌第十二集團軍，我們將要啟動第三軍團。
Do I get it?
我會得到第三軍團嗎？
I'll be honest with you.
我老實跟你說，
I've had reservations.
我有保留意見。
Then, you've been my senior ever since I left the academy.
那，我從軍校畢業後，你就一直是我的上級。
You were the boss in North Africa and Sicily, and I just thought, . . .
你在北非與西西里是我的頭，我有點顧慮，. . .
. . .well, it might be a problem for the both of us.
. . .這可能使我倆感到彆扭。
Uh, it wouldn't bother me.
喔，我這兒沒有問題。
There's one other thing. I don't want to hit this too hard. But, . . .
還有一件事，我並不想太強調這點。但是，. . .
. . .we're different kinds of people, George.
. . .我們是不同類型的人，喬治。
You're right, Brad. God damn it, every you're always right.
你說的對，布拉德。媽的，你一向都是對的。
With your brains and my screwy ideas, we make a wonderful team.
以你的頭腦與我的怪點子，我們是絕配。
We proved that in Sicily.
我們在西西里證明了這一點。
I tell it as truth, if I'd been your senior in Sicily, I would've relieved you.
我跟你說實話，如果我在西西里是你的上司，我會撤了你的職。
Brad, . . .
布拉德，. . .
. . .I'll crawl on my belly to get a command.
. . .我願意裝小狗，只要有仗打就行。
For God's sake, you got to get me in this fight.
看在上帝的份上，你一定要讓我參戰！
The only way I can get out of the doghouse. . .
我擺脫困境的唯一辦法. . .
. . .is to do something spectacular. I gotta get back in the war!
. . .是打一場漂亮的仗。我必須回來打仗！
My god, Hitler's own people tried to kill him a couple days ago.
老天，希特勒自己的人幾天前還企圖謀殺他。
First thing you know, it'll all be over and. . . .
在我們搞清楚之前，戰爭恐怕就結束了. . .
I'll. . .
我會. . .
. . .keep my mouth shut up. I'll behave myself.
. . .閉嘴，我會謹言慎行。
I give you my word.
我向你保證。
George, . . .
喬治，. . .
. . .I've been working on a plan called Cobra.
. . .我正在擬定「眼鏡蛇」計劃。
I'd like to know what you think of it.
我想知道你的想法。
Now, we've been slugging our way through hedgerow country, . . .
現在，我們在樹籬地區艱難前行，. . .
. . .half an acre a day, and we've got to find a way break out.
. . .每天才推進半英畝，我們必須找出突破的方法。
I want to use this road.
我想利用這條道路。
The Saint Lo-Periers road.
聖羅到皮埃爾的道路。
We'll let Monty pin down the enemy forces at Cannes.
我們將讓蒙蒂釘住戛納的敵軍。
We'll pulverize an area 3.5 miles wide with saturation bombing.
我們將以地毯式轟炸炸平三英里半寬的地區。
Then seven divisions will follow through.
然後以七個師跟進。
The 3rd Army will swing around here, a sweeping end run right across France.
第三軍團在這裡迂迴，橫掃穿過法國
What do you think?
你認為呢？
I think you need a screwball old horse cavalryman to command the 3rd Army.
我認為你需要一位騎兵老怪物來指揮第三軍團。
George, . . .
喬治，
. . .Ike ... came to that conclusion in London three months ago.
. . .艾克 ... 3個月之前在倫敦就已經定下來了。
He what?
他什麼？
Why, that dirty son ... !  I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
為什麼，那個狗娘養的 ... ！ 對不起，對不起。
I promise to keep my mouth shut.
我答應閉嘴的。
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
What's this activity near Coutances?
在庫坦斯附近的活動是什麼？
Enemy armored forces driving through our defenses at Lessay.
敵方裝甲部隊在拉塞突破我方防禦。
"American tanks moving rapidly, slicing through to the rear areas".
美軍坦克迅速前進穿過敵軍後方。
This sounds like Patton, Field Marshal.
這聽來像是巴頓，元帥。
Patton is in England.
巴頓在英格蘭。
Do we know this?
我們確認這是事實嗎？
The landing in Normandy is merely a diversionary maneuver.
諾曼底登陸只是聲東擊西的陽動。
The real invasion will come at Calais and Patton will lead it.
真正的入侵在加萊，而且將由巴頓率領。
The Fuhrer says that the Fifteenth Army is not to be moved to Normandy.
元首說第十五軍團不應調到諾曼底。
Those men are sitting on the beach at Calais throwing pebbles at each other...
十五軍團坐在加萊海灘閒扔石頭
...while our men are being slaughtered in Normandy.
...但是我軍在諾曼底卻遭到屠殺。
The Fifteenth Army is waiting for Patton at Calais and he will land there.
第十五軍團在加萊等待巴頓，而且他會在那裡登陸。
You seem perfectly willing to accept this nonsense, Jodl.
你似乎完全願意接受這種鬼話，約德爾。
Why?
為什麼？
Because I am not prepared to dispute the Fuhrer.
因為我必須與元首保持一致。
You'd think George would at least have the courtesy to let us know where he's going.
巴頓至少出於禮貌也得告訴我們他的方位。
Good God, look at that. Where you going, general?
老天，你看那裡！你要去哪裡，將軍？
Berlin.
柏林！
I'm going to personally shoot that paper-hanging son of a bitch.
我要去親手槍斃那個狗娘養的希特勒。
(CHEERING)
巴頓第三軍團造成的傷亡
陣亡、負傷、失蹤
Now, Hold it. Hold it. Hold it!
現在，等一下。等一下。等一下！
Even this place isn't on the map.
在地圖上沒有這個地方。
You know why? We've run clear off the map.
你知道為什麼嗎？我們已經跑到地圖之外了！
Give George a headline, and he's good for another 30 miles.
給喬治上一次頭條，他就能再推進30英里。
(HONKING)
-Atten ... hut!
-Badly!
立 ... 正！  一團糟！
Hold it!
好了，停止！
By now, look please, pay attention. We'll clean this mess up right now.
現在，都看好，注意。我們現在就清理這團混亂。
Let's move this vehicle out this way. This one out this way.
這輛車向這邊移動，這輛向這邊。
Back that thing up there, and we'll take this one here.
那輛向後退，我們開動這一輛。
All right, get up off your ass. Let's go, now!
好了，都站起來出發！現在出發，馬上！
That's it. That's the way to move. Good boy!
就是這樣。往那邊走。好樣的！
All right, come on.
好的，繼續。
Come on, now. Here we go. Come on. That's it!
繼續，趕快。往這方走。繼續。就是這樣！
That's it! Gun it!
就是這樣！快點！
Gun that thing!
那輛車開過來！
Okay, come on.
好的，繼續！
Watch it!
注意！
Go, go, go! Come on! Hold it up.
快，快，快！開上來！這邊等等。
Come on, baby! Yeah, yeah! Come on!
繼續，小子！好的，好的！繼續！
That's it.
就是這樣！
Come on, now.
繼續，趕快。
-Chet.
-Yeah, will do.
去叫他。  是，遵命！
Come on, keep coming! Keep coming! Hold it up there.
繼續，不要停！不要停！那邊停住！
Now come on! Hold it!
現在開動！那邊停住！
Hey, dummy! Hold the Friggin' tank!
嗨，笨蛋！停住那輛坦克！
Bad it.
糟糕了。
That's it. Come on.
就是這樣。繼續。
Good boy!
好樣的！
-Hold it up there!
-General!
那邊停住！  將軍！
General Bradley wants to have a word with you. (All right.) Down there.
布拉德利將軍想在那邊跟你談一談。(好的。) 就在那邊。
Okay. Come on!
好的。繼續！
Okay. Hold it up! Take over.
好的。停住！交給你了。
George, you'd make a good traffic cop.
喬治，你真是個優秀的交警。
George, this drive to the Seine has been absolutely magnificent.
喬治，這次向塞納河的推進真是好極了。
But I'm sorry to say, but I have to slow you down.
但是我很抱歉，我必須要你慢下來。
-What the hell for?
-(???) We'll have to cut off your supplies.
那是為什麼？
我們目前必須暫時切斷給你的補給。
Gasoline, ammunition, everything. We're check up against new priorities.
汽油、彈藥，全都切斷。歐洲盟軍最高總部面對新一套優先策略。
-I think I smell Montgomery.
-All right, take it easy, George.
我好像聞到蒙哥馬利的味道。  好了，別動氣，喬治。
There are serious issues involved. There're political prolocutor.
這是相當棘手的問題。這涉及嚴肅的政治議題。
By God, it is Montgomery.
老天，真的是蒙哥馬利！
The launching sites for the V-2 bombs are all in his area.
V-2飛彈發射場全都在他的區域內。
Mr.Churchill wants those rocket bases destroyed.
邱吉爾先生想要摧毀全部的飛彈基地。
Hitler kills more civilians in London than soldiers on the field.
希特勒發射飛彈在倫敦殺死的平民比在戰場殺死的士兵還多。
They expect Montgomery to do anything about it?
他們期待蒙哥馬利幹完這一切嗎？
You give me that gasoline and I'll gain ground with that, I'll kill Germans, too.
你給我汽油，我就會有進展，而且我也會殺德軍。
Give me 400,000 gallons. I'll go to Berlin.
給我40萬加侖，我會推進到柏林！
George, I can't do it.
喬治，我不能這樣
Bradley, the Siegfried line is an empty shell.
布拉德，齊格弗裡德防線是空殼子。
They've stripped the equipment and sent it eastern front.
他們已經拆掉所有的裝備送到東線。
It's over growing crawling with cows. I can punch through in two days.
它長滿了雜草而且牛群漫步。我兩天之內就能穿越它。
There's no use that arguing with me. It wasn't my idea.
和我爭論沒有作用，這不是我的主意。
If you wantn't me kill enemy. Why did you pick me to command?
如果你不讓我殺敵，為什麼你要挑我來當指揮官？
I didn't picked you.
我沒有挑選你。
Ike picked you.
是艾克挑你的！
George, you have performed brilliantly.
喬治，你有傑出的表現。
You are loyal, dedicated.
你忠誠、勇於奉獻。
You're one of the best field commanders I've got, but you don't know when to shut up.
你是我最優秀的戰地指揮官之一，但你就是不知道什麼時候該閉嘴。
George, you're a pain in the neck!
喬治，你真讓人頭痛！
I have a lot of faults, Brad.
我是有許多缺點，布拉德。
But ingratitude isn't one of them.
但不包括不知恩圖報。
I owe you a lot.
我欠你很多。
Hell, I know I'm a prima donna. I admit it.
哎，我知道我喜怒無常，我承認這是事實。
What I can't stand about Monty is, he won't admit it.
我不能忍受蒙蒂的是，他一直不肯承認自己的不足。
(TANK SPUTTERS)
Captain, Bailey's run out of gas.
上尉，貝利沒汽油了。
The point tank has run out, too.
尖兵坦克也沒汽油了。
And there's a Kraut column up ahead.
但是前面有德軍縱隊。
Yeah, I know.
是的，我知道。
Were you in command here, captain?
這裡是你指揮的嗎，上尉？
I was in command.
本來是我指揮的。
My tank platoon was supporting an infantry company.
我的坦克排支援步兵連。
Tanks ran out of gas, so we had to fight it out.
坦克沒汽油了，所以我們必須決一死戰。
We started 11:00 clock last night.
我們昨晚11點開戰，
Finished a couple hours ago.
兩小時前結束。
This morning the fighting was hand-to-hand.
今早是肉搏戰。
I had a dream last night.
我昨晚作了一個夢。
In my dream it came to me, . . .
我的夢帶我到這裡，. . .
. . .that right now the whole Nazi Reich is mine for the taking.
. . .我夢見整個納粹帝國現在任我攻佔。
Thank about that, Cod. I was nearly sent home in disgrace.
感謝這場戰爭，考德。我差點被不光彩地遣送回國。
Now I have precisely the right instrument, . . .
現在我正好擁有了恰當的途徑，. . .
. . .at precisely the right moment of history, and in exactly the right place.
. . .正好處於歷史上恰當的時機，正好位於恰當的地點。
The Saar?
薩爾區？
This will change, too, very quickly, . . .
這個戰機轉瞬即逝，. . .
. . .like a planet spinning off into the universe.
. . .就像流星在天空中飛逝而去。
A moment like this won't come again for 1000 years. All I need is. . .
這是千載難逢的戰機。我需要的只是. . .
. . .a few miserable gallons of gasoline.
. . .一些汽油。
Right now, the weak spot is here.
現在，弱點在這裡。
In 10 days, we could be in Berlin.
在10天之內，我們就能抵達柏林。
What about the fortifications at Verdun and Metz?
那凡爾登與梅斯的防禦工事呢？
Fixed fortifications are. . .
固定防禦工事是. . .
. . .monuments to the stupidity of man.
. . .人類愚昧的紀念碑。
Now, when mountain ranges and oceans could be overcome, . . .
當今，當山脈與大洋都能被征服時，. . .
. . .anything built by man can be overcome.
. . .任何人造建築都能被征服。
You know how I'm sure they're finished out there?
你知道我為什麼肯定他們已經完蛋了？
The carts.
那些手推車。
They're using carts to move their wounded and their supplies.
他們用手推車來搬運他們的傷員和補給。
The carts came to me in my dream, . . .
手推車出現在我夢中，. . .
. . .kept buzzing around my head. I couldn't figure it out.
. . .它們不斷在我腦海飛旋。我無法想通。
Then I remembered. . .
然後我記起來. . .
. . .that nightmare in the snow, the endless, the agonizing retreat from Moscow.
. . .那個冰天雪地中的夢魘，漫無邊際，從莫斯科無盡痛苦的撤退。
How cold it was!
多麼寒冷的天氣！
They took the wounded and what's left of the supplies and threw them on the carts.
他們把傷員與僅存的補給放在手推車上。
Napoleon was finished!
拿破侖完蛋了！
Not any color left. Not even the red of blood.
沒有軍旗的炫目招展，甚至沒有映紅的鮮血。
Only the snow.
只有大雪。
Look at this, Cod.
看看這些，考德。
I love it.
我愛它。
God help me, I do love it so.
上帝保佑，我真的如此愛它。
I love it more than my life.
我愛它勝過愛我的生命。
盟軍解放巴黎
Paris is liberated, and French troops lead the way.
巴黎解放了，法國軍隊繼續前進。
The Allies march into the historic city after four years of Nazi occupation.
盟軍在納粹佔領四年之後大踏步進入這座歷史名城。
The hard-fighting French 2nd Armored Division. . .
艱苦奮戰的法國第二裝甲師. . .
. . .under Major General Jacques Leclerc. . .
. . .在雷克勒克將軍的率領下. . .
. . .gets a welcome they will never forget. . .
. . .獲得永誌不忘的歡迎. . .
. . .as they enter their beloved Paris.
. . .當進入他們鍾愛的巴黎時。
蒙哥馬利進入比利時
In a powerful drive to the north, . . .
在向北面的強大推進中，. . .
...British General Montgomery cuts off and bypasses the French coastal towns...
...英國將領蒙哥馬利切斷並繞過法國海岸城鎮...
. . .of Boulogne, Calais and Dunkirk, . . .
. . .布倫、加萊與敦克爾克，. . .
. . .pushing on to capture the vital Belgian port of Antwerp.
. . .繼續推進奪取重要的比利時港口安特衛普。
巴頓衝向德國
Meanwhile, the main body of Patton's army, . . .
同時，巴頓軍團的主力，. . .
. . .resupplied now and rolling like a juggernaut, is slicing toward the Saar.
. . .重新得到補給變得勢不可當，正在攻向薩爾地區。
Nazi resistance appears to crumbling, . . .
納粹的抵抗似乎正在瓦解，. . .
. . .and it seems that nothing can stop our troops from driving on into the heart of Germany.
. . .似乎沒有任何力量能夠阻止我軍繼續衝向德國心臟。
-Sir, General Bradley on your line.
-Good, good.
長官，布拉德利將軍有電話打來。  好的，好的。
Brad, listen, I've got a bridgehead across the Saar.
布拉德，聽我說，我有橋頭堡跨越薩爾地區。
I'm on my way to Germany.
我正在開向德國的路上。
Wait a minute, George! There's a lot of trouble up north.
等一等，喬治！北邊的麻煩還很多。
Uh, liston I, I want you to transfer 10th Armored to Middleton's 8th Corps right away.
啊，聽我說，我要你立即把第十裝甲師轉調給米德爾頓的第八軍。
Uh, Brad, you can't do that!
啊，布拉德，你不能那樣做！
George, ah, listen, I don't have time to argue.
喬治，聽著，我沒有時間爭論。
There's a lot of enemy activity up around Ardennes.
阿登附近有很多敵軍活動。
No, I don't know how serious it is, but. . .
不，我不知道有多嚴重，但是. . .
. . .Ike wants us to meet with Bedell Smith tomorrow at Verdun.
. . .艾克要我們明天在凡爾登與史密斯開會。
Be there at 1100.
11點到那裡。
Yes, sir.
是的，長官。
右轉到霍發裡茲
There's absolutely no reason for us to assume. . .
我們絕沒有理由假設. . .
. . .that the Germans are mounting a major offensive.
. . .德軍會發動重大攻勢。
The weather is awful. Their supplies are low.
天氣惡劣，他們的補給不足。
The Germans army hasn't mounted a winter attack since Frederick the Great.
自從弗雷德裡克大帝以後，德國軍隊就從未發動過冬季攻勢。
Therefore I believe that's exactly what they're going to do.
因此我相信，那正是他們將要做的事。
聖維特
不准停車
All right, I want you to start making contingency plans, . . .
好了，我要各位開始制定突擊計劃，. . .
. . .for pulling out of our eastward attack, . . .
. . .撤出我們向東的進攻，. . .
. . .changing directions 90 degrees, moving up to Luxembourg.
. . .調轉90度，向北前往盧森堡。
Don't look so stunned, gentlemen.
不用這麼吃驚，各位。
I want you to plan for three possible axes of attack, . . .
我要各位擬定三條可能的進攻路線，. . .
. . .from Diekirch, due north; . . .
. . .從迪克西向正北；. . .
. . .from Arlen to, ah, Bastogne; . . .
. . .從阿隆到巴斯通；. . .
. . .from Neufchatel against the German left flank.
. . .從紐弗堡攻向德軍左側。
馬爾梅蒂
We've identified four German armies, . . .
我們辨認出四個德軍軍團：. . .
. . .the 7th, 5th Panzer, 6th S.S Panzer and the 15th.
. . .第七、第五裝甲軍團，黨衛軍第六裝甲軍團與第十五軍團
They've beat us with 26 divisions.
他們用26個師進攻我們。
They've overran two regimens of the 106th Division, . . .
他們擊垮了第106師的兩個團，. . .
. . .and 7500 of our men were forced to surrender.
. . .我軍7500人被迫投降。
Our immediate concern is that von Rundstedt, . . .
我們最緊急的是在倫德斯特把，. . .
. . .has the 101st Airborne is trapped here at Bastogne.
. . .我們的第101空降師被圍困在巴斯通。
Bastogne, by the way, is the key to this entire area.
巴斯通，也就是這個地區的樞紐。
If we can hold it, we can break up the entire German offensive.
如果我們能夠守住它，就能瓦解德軍的整個攻勢。
If they take it, we're in serious trouble.
如果德軍攻下它，我們的麻煩就大了。
Ike wants to know if anybody can get at there and relieve. . .
艾克想知道有沒有人能到那裡在
. . .the 101st before they're torn to pieces.
101師被粉碎之前解圍。
I'm afraid there's nothing that Field Marshal Montgomery can do.
恐怕蒙哥馬利元帥無能為力了。
General, nothing for some weeks.
將軍，至少在幾個星期之內。
What about you, George?
你呢，喬治？
I can attack with three divisions in 48 hours.
我可以在48小時內以三個師進攻。
I'd give myself some leeway if I were you.
如果我是你的話，我會多給自己留些迴旋餘地。
Ike wants a realistic estimate, George.
艾克要的是務實的估計，喬治。
Jural you're in the middle of a fight now. It's, ... It's over a hundred miles to Bastogne.
準確地說，你目前正在交戰，而且，... 而且離巴斯通還有100多英里。
My staff's already working out the details.
我的參謀正在解決突擊的細節問題。
Ah, frankly, I don't see how it's possible, . . .
啊，坦白地說，我看不出那怎麼可能，. . .
. . .not in this kind of weather.
. . .在這種天氣下是不可能的。
I should've thought you'd want to fall back and regroup.
我認為你的部隊需要撤下來修整。
Not me. Freddie, I don't like to pay for the same real estate twice.
我不需要。弗雷迪，我不喜歡得而復失。
But what about your men?
但是你的部下呢？
You can't cart them off 100 miles then expect them to attack without rest.
你不可能強行軍100英里，然後指望部隊不休整就立刻開始進攻！
I trained these men, Arthur. They'll do what I tell them.
部隊是我帶出來的，亞瑟。他們會照我的命令去做。
Ah, Perhaps we hadn't realized you were quite so popular with your troops, general.
啊，我們沒想到你這麼受部隊歡迎，將軍。
I'm not. They'll do it because they're good soldiers, . . .
並非是我受歡迎，他們這樣做全是因為他們是出色的士兵，. . .
. . .and because they realize, as I do, that we can still lose this war.
. . .而且他們與我一樣都知道，我們還有可能輸掉這場戰爭。
Hmm. I think I can speak for Field Marshal Montgomery.
喔，請允許我代表蒙哥馬利元帥發言。
He'd say you're asking the impossible of your men.
他會說你在要求部下做不可能的事。
Of course he would, . . .
他會這麼說，. . .
. . .cause he's never realized that's what we're in business for.
. . .因為他從沒想到過，我們來就是專門幹不可能之事的。
(BOMB EXPLODES)
Sir, General McAuliffe turned down a German surrender demand.
長官，麥考利夫將軍拒絕了德軍的招降。
You know what he said?
你猜他是怎麼說的？
What?
怎麼說？
He said, "Nuts. "
他說：「去你的。」
Keep them moving, colonel.
全速推進，上校。
A man that eloquent has to be saved.
一定要解救那些有口才的人。
巴斯通
(SILENCE)
德國佬殺手
This is where it pays off, . . .
這就是回報，. . .
. . .the training and discipline.
. . .嚴酷訓練與嚴明軍紀的回報。
No other outfit in the world, . . .
世界上沒有任何一支部隊，. . .
. . .could pull out of a winter battle, move a hundred miles, . . .
. . .能夠這樣撤出冬季的惡戰，強行軍100英里，. . .
. . .go into a major attack with no rest, no sleep, no hot food.
. . .立刻展開強勢進攻，既不休整、不睡覺，還吃不上熱飯菜。
God! God, I'm proud of these men!
上帝啊！上帝，我為他們感到驕傲！
Sir, von Rundstedt's thrown another panzer division against Bastogne.
長官，德軍又投入一個裝甲師進攻巴斯通。
101st Airborne's holding on by its fingernails.
第101空降師岌岌可危了。
Damn air cover's what we need. With 24 hours decent weather, we might make it.
我們需要該死的空中掩護。至少得有24小時像樣的天氣，我們才能出動。
General Mason, sir.
梅森將軍接通了，長官。
Hello, Mase. Listen, we're short on foot soldiers.
你好，梅森。聽我說，我們缺乏步兵。
I want you to cannibalize your anti-aircraft units and turn them into riflemen.
我要你調集防空部隊，並轉為步兵。
Yes, every damn one of them what you might find.
對！你得找出每一個能用的人！
Good evening, general.
晚上好，將軍。
I just got the weather report for tomorrow, more snow.
我剛拿到明天的天氣預報，更多的雪。
There goes our air cover.
空中掩護也沒戲了。
Sir, we may have to pay lot of wait for better weather.
長官，我們可能必須停下來，等待天氣好轉。
Brave men dying up there. I'm not going to wait. Not an hour, not a minute.
那些勇敢的士兵在送命，我不能再等待。一分一秒都不能等待！
Going to keep moving.
我們要繼續前進。
Is that clear?
清楚了嗎？
We're going to attack all night and attack tomorrow morning!
我們要整夜前行，我們要在明天早晨進攻！
If we're not victorious, . . .
如果我們不成功，. . .
. . .let no one come back alive.
. . .就一個都不要想活著回去。
You know something, general?
你知道嗎，將軍？
Sometimes, they can't tell when you're acting and when you're not.
有時，他們真不知道你是在虛張聲勢，還是認真的。
It isn't important for them to know.
他們是否知道並不重要，
It's only important for me to know.
只有我是否知道才是最重要的。
-You want to see me, general?
-Oh, yes, chaplain.
您找我，將軍？  是的，牧師。
I'm sick and tired of 3rd Army having to fight Germans, . . .
我煩透了，第三軍團必須進攻德軍，. . .
. . .it's supreme command, no gasoline, . . .
. . .這是最高命令。現在，卻沒汽油，. . .
. . .and now this ungodly weather.
. . .現在還遇到這種鬼天氣。
I want a prayer, a weather prayer.
我要進行一次祈禱，祈求好天氣。
A weather prayer, sir?
祈求好天氣，長官？
Yes, let's see if you can't get God working with us on this thing.
對！看看你能否祈求上帝與我們一起戰鬥。
Take a thick rug for that kind of praying.
這種禱告恐怕很困難。
I don't care if it takes a flying carpet.
我不管它有多困難。
Well, I don't know how this will be received, general.
喔，我不知道上帝會怎麼想，將軍。
Praying for good weather so we can kill our fellow man.
祈求好天氣，以便我們能夠去殺人。
I can assure you, clergy, because of my intimate relations with the Almighty, . . .
我可以向你保證，牧師，因為我和全能的神關係很好，. . .
. . .if you write a good prayer, we'll have good weather.
. . .如果你寫一篇好禱文，我們就會得到好天氣。
And I expect that prayer within an hour.
並且，我在1小時內就需要禱文。
Yes, sir.
是的，長官。
"Almighty and most merciful Father, . . .
全能與最慈悲的天父，. . .
. . .we humbly beseech Thee. . .
. . .我們謙卑地祈求您. . .
. . .of Thy great goodness. . .
. . .大發慈悲. . .
. . .to restrain this immoderate weather. . .
. . .阻止這種惡劣天氣. . .
. . .with which we've had to contend.
. . .這是我們必須爭取的。
Grant us fair weather for battle.
賜與我們戰鬥所需要的好天氣。
Graciously hearken to us. . .
恩賜傾聽我們. . .
. . .as soldiers who call upon Thee, . . .
. . .這些軍人的呼喚，. . .
. . .that armed with Thy power, . . .
. . .這支軍隊憑著您的大能，. . .
. . .we may advance from victory to victory. . .
. . .我們得以接連勝利. . .
. . .and crush the oppression. . .
. . .並且粉碎敵人的壓迫. . .
. . .and wickedness of our enemies, . . .
. . .和為非作歹，. . .
. . .and establish Thy justice. . .
. . .以此來建立您的正義. . .
. . .among men and nations.''
. . .在世間諸國之中。」
Amen!
阿門！
Weather's perfect！
天氣好極了！
Cod, get me that chaplain.
卡德，把那個牧師找來。
He stands in good with the Lord, and I want to decorate him.
他和上帝的關係很好，我要給他勳章！
Hiya, general!
您好，將軍！
嗨，艾克！想贏嗎？讓喬治來幹！
旅行家在此！
巴斯通 解圍
Supported by medium bombers and fighter bombers. . .
在中型轟炸機與戰鬥機的支援下，. . .
. . .which flying countless sorties against German positions, . . .
. . .對德軍陣地發動了無數次進攻，. . .
. . .elements of the 3rd Army, . . .
. . .以第三軍團為主力，. . .
. . .spearheaded by the 4th Armored Division, . . .
. . .以第四裝甲師為先鋒，. . .
. . .drive into the besieged city of Bastogne. . .
. . .大部隊攻進了被圍的巴斯通. . .
. . .to relieve its 18,000 defenders, . . .
. . .解圍了18,000名守軍，. . .
. . .on the day after Christmas.
. . .就在聖誕節後第二天。
During this operation, 3rd Army moved farther and faster. . .
在這次戰役中，第三軍團比美國歷史上任何部隊行軍更遠、更快，. . .
. . .and engaged more divisions in less time. . .
. . .在最短時間裡. . .
. . .than any other army in the history of the United States.
. . .與最多的德軍機械化師進行激戰。
This is the end，the end.
戰爭結束了，的確該結束了。
Hurry, Steiger. I want everything destroyed. Papers, maps, everything!
快，史泰格，我要毀掉每一樣東西。
文件、地圖，全都毀掉！
Everything will be destroyed, General, that I can promise you.
好的，每樣東西都將毀掉，將軍。保證完成任務。
I'll never let the Russians take me! I'll kill myself, like the Fuhrer!
我絕不讓俄國人俘虜！
我會像元首一樣自己了斷！
He, too, will be destroyed.
他也到了斷的時候了。
The absence of war will kill him.
戰爭結束了，他就謝幕了。
The pure warrior. . .
為戰爭而存在. . .
. . .a magnificent anachronism.
. . .與這個時代格格不入。
(MUSlC PLAYS)
Excuse me, sir.
打擾了，閣下。
General Katkov would like to know whether you'll join him. . .
朱可夫將軍想知道，您是否願與他. . .
. . .to drink to the surrender of Germany.
. . .舉杯共飲，慶祝德國投降。
My compliments to the general.
我向將軍致意。
Please inform him that I don't care to drink with him. . .
請告訴他，我不想與他. . .
. . .or any other Russian son of a bitch.
. . .或者任何狗娘養的俄國人共飲。
Sir, I. . .
閣下，我. . .
. . .I cannot tell the general that!
. . .我不能轉告將軍那種話！
You tell him that.
你告訴他。
Tell him word for word.
一字不差地告訴他。
(SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN)
（俄語）
The general says he thinks that. . .
將軍說，他認為. . .
. . .you are a son of a bitch, too.
. . .您也是狗娘養的。
Okay. I'll drink to that.
好，我願為此乾一杯。
One son of a bitch to another.
狗娘養的敬狗娘養的。
(SPEAKS IN RUSSIAN)
（俄語）
(CHEERING)
General, is it true the President Roosevelt, before he died, . . .
將軍，羅斯福總統去世前真的. . .
. . .promised you a combat command in the Pacific?
. . .許諾過你指揮太平洋戰區嗎？
Yes, he did, but now that he's gone, I doubt there's much chance of that.
是的，但現在他去世了，我想機會很渺茫了。
Doug MacArthur doesn't want me up there.
道格·麥克阿瑟不想要我去那邊。
We're told about these "wonder weapons" the Germans were working on, . . .
我們聽說德國人正在研究一種「神奇武器」，. . .
long-range rockets, push-button bombing, . . .
遠程飛彈，按鈕轟炸，. . .
. . .weapons that don't need soldiers.
. . .不需要士兵的武器。
"Wonder weapon" ?
「神奇武器」？
My God, I don't see the wonder in them.
老天，我看不出它們有什麼神奇之處。
Killing without heroics, nothing is glorified, nothing is reaffirmed?
沒有英雄氣概的殺伐，沒有榮耀，沒有認同？
No heroes, no cowards, no troops, ... No generals?
沒了英雄，沒了懦夫，沒了部隊，...就連將軍也沒有？
Only those who are left alive and those who are left ... dead.
只剩下倖存者與 ... 死者的區別。
I'm glad I won't live to see it.
我很高興不會活著看到那一天。
It's said, general, you're still using former Nazis in key positions. . .
我們聽說，將軍，你仍然留用以前的納粹官員擔任要職，. . .
. . .despite the official denazification policy.
. . .而不顧官方正在消除納粹影響政策。
Well, if I'm supplied with trained personnel, I'll get rid of the Nazis.
是的，如果能得到足夠的訓練有素的人手，我就不會用納粹。
Until then, I'll use pepole who run the railroads and keep the telephones working.
而現在，我只用他們維持鐵路與電話正常運轉。
After all, general, didn't most ordinary Nazis join the Party. . .
是否可以這樣說，將軍，大部份普通的納粹黨員入黨. . .
. . .it about the same way Americans become Republicans or Democrats?
. . .都像美國人加入共和黨或民主黨一般稀鬆平常？
Yes, that's about it.
是的，大致是那樣。
You do agree, don't you, general, that our national policy should be made by civilians, and not by the military?
您是否贊同我們國家的政策應該由文人而非軍人來制定？
Of course, I agree. But the politicians never let us finish.
當然，我同意。但是，政客們的政策無法讓軍隊馬放南山。
They always stop short, and leave us with another war to fight.
它們總有缺陷，經過短時期的停戰後，又讓軍人不得不面對另一場戰爭
Are you thinking about our Russian allies?
您指的是我們的俄國盟友？
Heh.
嗨。
Sir, did you say if you found your army was between the Germans and the Russians, . . .
將軍，你說如果你的部隊位於德軍與俄軍之間，. . .
. . .you'd attack in both directions?
. . .你會兩邊都打嗎？
No, I never said that.
不，我從沒說那句話。
I never said any such thing.
我從沒說那樣的話。
But I wish I had.(LAUGHING)
但是，我但願我說過。
Sir, there's a call on your line from supreme headquarters, General Smith.
長官，您的熱線上有最高統帥部史密斯將軍的電話。
Bedell?
畢托？
Ike is furious.
艾克氣瘋了！
How could you possibly compare Republicans and Democrats to the Nazi Party?
你怎能把共和黨與民主黨比喻成納粹黨呢？
And this statement that you refuse to Denazify. . .
你拒絕消滅納粹的說法. . .
. . .has everybody screaming. The Russians, the British, everybody.
. . .讓各方面輿論嘩然，包括俄國人、英國人，任何一方！
Well, the hell with the Mongoloid Russians.
好吧，叫蒙古佬俄國人去死吧。
We've given them Berlin, given them Prague, God knows what else.
我們給他們柏林、布拉格，天知道還給些了什麼。
Are we letting them dictate policy, too?
還要讓他們統治世界嗎？
George, don't be a fool.
喬治，不要再犯傻了。
The war in Europe is over. Washington dictates policy.
歐洲戰事已經結束了，一切都得聽從華盛頓的安排。
The war shouldn't be over. We should stop pussyfooting about the goddamn Russians!
歐洲戰事不應該結束。我們不應該再對他娘的俄國人縮手縮腳！
We'll have to fight them sooner or later anyway. Why not do it now, when our army's here, do it anywhere?
我們早晚都要和他們打一場。為什麼不趁我們軍隊還在歐洲的時候打一仗。
Instead of disarming Germans, we'd ally get them to fight the Bolsheviks.
不要解除德軍武裝，我們應該聯合他們，打擊布爾什維克。
George, you better shut up. This line may be tapped.
喬治，你最好閉嘴。電話可能會被竊聽。
I don't give a damn. That I'll tell you something, Bedell, . . .
我才不管呢。我要告訴你一件事，畢托，. . .
. . .up till now, we've been fighting the wrong people.
. . .到現在為止，我們都搞錯了戰爭的對象。
Now, You and Ike don't have to get involved, you're so damn soft about it.
現在，你與艾克都不用出面，你們對俄國人都太他媽的軟弱了。
You leave it to me. In 10 days I'll have us a war with the son of a bitch, . . .
你們就交給我吧。在10天內，我就會和那些狗娘養的俄國人開戰，. . .
. . .and I'll make it look like their fault!
. . .而且會讓它看來是俄國人挑起的！
George, you're mad. You're absolutely out of your mind!
喬治，你瘋了，你完全是說的瘋話！
Well, I'm no diplomat.
是的，我不懂外交藝術！
I'm a combat soldier. That's all these jokers understand.
我只知道打打殺殺，那些小丑只會這麼想。
You get Ike to give me the word, and I'll kick them behind back to Russia where they belong!
你只要讓艾克下令給我，我就會踢他們回到他們該待的俄國。
Shall I call the artist back, sir?
要我把畫家叫回來嗎，長官？
No, the hell with him.
不用，不用管他了。
Nobody wants to see a picture of me. I'm mad!
沒有人想看我的畫像，我瘋了！
Don't you know that!?
你難道不知道嗎！？
歐洲盟軍最高統帥艾森豪威爾將軍司令部
Field Marshal Montgomery, . . .
蒙哥馬利元帥，. . .
. . .his Majesty is prepared to receive. . .
. . .陛下準備接見. . .
. . .the next chief of the imperial general staff.
. . .下一任大英帝國的參謀總長。
Thank you!
謝謝你！
And thank you!
Thank you, major!
謝謝你，少校！
Take care of yourself, Cod!
請多保重，考德！
George, thank you!
喬治，謝謝你！
Thank you!
謝謝你！
Well, uhh, gentlemen, . . .
好了，啊，各位，. . .
. . .all good things must come to an end.
. . .天下沒有不散的筵席。
And the best thing that's happened to me in my life, . . .
我一生最幸福的事就是，. . .
. . .has been, uh , uh, the honor and privilege of commanding the 3rd Army.
. . .有幸得以指揮第三軍團。
Goodbye!. . .
再見！. . .
. . .and God bless you!
. . .願上帝保佑各位！
Brad, they've, uh, . . .
布拉德，他們，啊，. . .
. . .taken the 3rd Army away from me.
. . .從我手裡拿走了第三軍團。
I know.
我知道。
I just thought we could have dinner together tonight.
我只是想今晚與你共進晚餐。
Thank you, Brad. That's. . .
謝謝你，布拉德。那. . .
. . .damn thoughtful. I appreciate it.
. . .你考慮得真周到，我很感激。
Right now, I think I'll take Willie for a walk.
現在，我想帶威利去散散步。
George, look out!
喬治，注意！
After all I've been through, . . .
我什麼都歷經過了，. . .
. . .imagine getting killed by an oxcart.
. . .想不到差點被一輛牛車撞死。
No, Brad, there's only one proper way for a professional soldier to die, . . .
布拉德，一個職業軍人只有一種恰當的死法，. . .
. . .from the last bullet of the last battle of the last war.
. . .死於最後一場戰鬥、最後一役的最後一顆子彈。
At least the 3rd Army earned its pay.
至少第三軍名不虛傳。
In our drive across Europe, we liberated. . .
在我們橫掃歐洲的戰鬥裡，我們解放了. . .
. . . 12,000 cities and towns, . . .
. . . 12,000 座城鎮，. . .
. . .and inflicted a million and a half enemy casualties.
. . .而且使敵人死傷了150萬。
I have a feeling from now on, just being a good soldier won't mean a thing.
我覺得今後作為一個好軍人已經沒有什麼意義了。
I'm afraid we're gonna have to be diplomats, administrators, you name it.
恐怕我們必須去當外交官與行政人員，就像你說的那樣。
God help us!
願上帝保佑我們！
George, I want to say one thing.
喬治，我想告訴你一件事。
You've done a magnificent job here in Europe.
你在歐洲幹得非常出色。
That's right, George.
那是真的，喬治。
I think that soldier you slapped in Sicily. . .
我認為在西西里被你打耳光的那個士兵，. . .
. . .did more to win the war than any other private in the army.
. . .在戰鬥中的貢獻比誰都大。
I'll see you for dinner.
我們晚餐見。
Six-thirty?
六點半？
[Willy Barking]
For over a thousand years, . . .
一千多年以前，. . .
. . .Roman conquerors returning from the wars, . . .
. . .羅馬征服者打完了勝仗凱旋而歸，. . .
. . .enjoyed the honor of a triumph, a tumultuous parade.
. . .享受著勝利的榮耀，盛大的歡迎遊行。
In the procession. . .
在行列裡，. . .
. . .came trumpeters and musicians and. . .
. . .有吹鼓手、樂隊以及. . .
. . .strange animals from the conquered territories, . . .
. . .來自被征服地區的珍禽異獸，. . .
. . .together with carts laden with treasure and captured armaments.
. . .還有滿載著一車車的珍寶和繳獲的武器。
The conqueror rode in a triumphal chariot, . . .
征服者站在凱旋的戰車裡，. . .
. . .the dazed prisoners walking in chains before him.
. . .前面走著戴鐐銬的俘虜。
Sometimes, his children robed in white, . . .
他的兒女有時身穿白袍，. . .
. . .stood with him in the chariot, or rode the trace horses.
. . .跟他一起站在戰車裡，或者騎馬相隨。
A slave stood behind the conqueror. . .
一個奴隸站在征服者的身後，
. . .holding a golden crown. . .
. . .手捧一頂金冠，
. . .and whispering in his ear a warning. . .
. . .在他耳邊低聲警告說：
. . .that all glory ... is fleeting!
. . .一切榮耀 ... 很快都會消失的！